<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH
	xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2017-03-31T01:42:03Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="ListRecords" resumptionToken="509567/oai_dc/300//" >http://aisel.aisnet.org/do/oai/</request>
	
	<ListRecords>
			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2658</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Cognitive Stopping Rules for Terminating Information Search in Online Tasks</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Browne, Glen J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pitts, Mitzi G.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wetherbe, James C.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Online search has become a significant activity in the daily lives of individuals throughout much of the world. The almost instantaneous availability of billions of Web pages has caused a revolution in the way people seek information. Despite the increasing importance of online search behavior in decision making and problem solving, very little is known about why people stop searching for information online. In this paper, we review the literature concerning online search and cognitive stopping rules, and then describe specific types of information search tasks. Based on this theoretical development, we generated hypotheses and conducted an experiment with 115 participants each performing three search tasks on the Web. Our findings show that people utilize a number of stopping rules to terminate search, and that the stopping rule used depends on the type of task performed. Implications for online information search theory and practice are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2007-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol31/iss1/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2658&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information search</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cognitive stopping rules</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online search behavior</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>decision making</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>task types and dimensions</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2659</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Understanding and Mitigating Uncertainty in Online Exchange Relationships:  A Principal-Agent Perspective</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pavlou, Paul A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liang, Huigang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xue, Yajiong</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Despite a decade since the inception of B2C e-commerce, the uncertainty of the online environment still makes many consumers reluctant to engage in online exchange relationships. Even if uncertainty has been widely touted as the primary barrier to online transactions, the literature has viewed uncertainty as a “background” mediator with insufficient conceptualization and measurement. To better understand the nature of uncertainty and mitigate its potentially harmful effects on B2C e-commerce adoption (especially for important purchases), this study draws upon and extends the principal-agent perspective to identify and propose a set of four antecedents of perceived uncertainty in online buyer-seller relationships – perceived information asymmetry, fears of seller opportunism, information privacy concerns, and information security concerns - which are drawn from the agency problems of adverse selection (hidden information) and moral hazard (hidden action).   To mitigate uncertainty in online exchange relationships, this study builds upon the principal-agent perspective to propose a set of four uncertainty mitigating factors – trust, website informativeness, product diagnosticity, and social presence - that facilitate online exchange relationships by overcoming the agency problems of hidden information and hidden action through the logic of signals and incentives.   The proposed structural model is empirically tested with longitudinal data from 521 consumers for two products (prescription drugs and books) that differ on their level of purchase involvement. The results support our model, delineating the process by which buyers engage in online exchange relationships by mitigating uncertainty. Interestingly, the proposed model is validated for two distinct targets, a specific website and a class of websites.   Implications for understanding and facilitating online exchange relationships for different types of purchases, mitigating uncertainty perceptions, and extending the principal-agent perspective are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2007-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol31/iss1/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2659&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Uncertainty</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>agency theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>adverse selection</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hidden information</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>moral hazard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hidden action</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>fears of seller opportunism</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information asymmetry</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information privacy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information security</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>trust</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>website informativeness</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>product diagnosticity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social presence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>book purchasing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online prescription filling.</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2660</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:54Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>E-Commerce Product Recommendation Agents:  Use, Characteristics, and Impact</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Xiao, Bo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benbasat, Izak</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Recommendation agents (RAs) are software that elicits the interests or preferences of individual consumers for products, either explicitly or implicitly, and make recommendations accordingly. RAs have the potential to support and improve the quality of the decisions consumers make when searching for and selecting products online. They can reduce the information overload facing consumers, as well as the complexity of online searches. Prior research on RAs has focused mostly on developing and evaluating different underlying algorithms that generate recommendations. This paper instead identifies other important aspects of RAs, namely RA use, RA characteristics, provider credibility, and factors related to product, user, and user-RA interaction, which influence users’ decision making processes and outcomes, as well as their evaluation of RAs. It goes beyond generalized models, such as TAM, and identifies the RA-specific features, such as RA input, process and output design characteristics, that affect users’ evaluations, including their assessments of the usefulness and ease-of-use of RA applications.  Based on a review of existing literature on e-commerce RAs, this paper develops a conceptual model with 28  propositions derived from five theoretical perspectives. The propositions help answer the two research questions: (1) How do RA use, RA characteristics, and other factors influence consumer decision making processes and outcomes? (2) How do RA use, RA characteristics, and other factors influence users’ evaluations of RAs?  By identifying the critical gaps between what we know and what we need to know, this paper identifies potential areas of future research for scholars. It also provides advice to IS practitioners concerning the effective design and development of RAs.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2007-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol31/iss1/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2660&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2592</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Author Index, Volume 30, 2006</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2592&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2593</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Subject Index, Volume 30, 2006</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2593&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2591</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Reviewer Volume 30, 2006</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/13</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2591&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2666</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>When Is Enough, Enough?</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2666&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2670</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Influence Processes for Information Technology Acceptance:  An Elaboration Likelihood Model</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Bhattacherjee, Anol</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sanford, Clive</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This study examines how processes of external influence shape information technology (IT) acceptance among potential users, how such influence effects vary across a user population, and the persistence of these effects over time.  Drawing on the elaboration-likelihood model (ELM), we compared two alternative influence processes, the central and peripheral routes, in motivating IT acceptance.  These processes were respectively operationalized using the argument quality and source credibility constructs, and linked to perceived usefulness and attitude, the core perceptual drivers of IT acceptance.  We further examined how these influence processes were moderated by users’ IT expertise and perceived job relevance and the temporal stability of the influence effects.  Nine hypotheses thus developed were empirically validated using a field survey of document management system acceptance at an eastern European governmental agency.  This study contributes to the IT acceptance literature by introducing ELM as a referent theory for acceptance research, by elaborating alternative modes of influence, and by specifying factors moderating their effects.  For practitioners, this study introduced influence processes as policy tools that managers can employ to motivate IT acceptance within their organizations, benchmarked alternative influence strategies, and demonstrated the need for customizing influence strategies to the specific needs of a user population.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2670&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information systems acceptance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>elaboration likelihood model</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>influence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>persuasion</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>attitude</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>survey research</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2671</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Real Options in Information Technology Risk Management:  An Empirical Validation of Risk-Option Relationships</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Benaroch, Michel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lichtenstein, Yossi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robinson, Karl</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Recently, an option-based risk management (OBRiM) framework has been proposed to control risk and maximize value in IT-investment decisions. While the framework is prescriptive in nature, its core logic rests on a set of normative risk-option mappings for choosing which particular real options to embed in an investment in order to control specific risks. This study tests empirically whether these mappings are observed in practice. The research site is a large Irish financial services organization with well established IT risk management practices not tied to any real options framework. Our analysis of the risk management plans developed for a broad portfolio of 50 IT investments finds ample empirical support for OBRiM’s risk-option mappings. This shows that IT managers follow the logic of option-based risk management, though purely based on intuition. Unfortunately, reliance on this logic based on intuition alone could lead to suboptimal or counterproductive risk management practices. We therefore argue that managerial intuition ought to be supplemented with the use of formal real option models, which allow for better quantitative insights into which risk mitigations to pursue and combine in order to effectively address the risks most worth controlling.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2671&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT investment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>risk</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>real options</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>risk management</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2672</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Understanding the Impact of Web Personalization on User Information Processing and Decision Outcomes</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Tam, Kar Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ying Ho, Shuk</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Personalized IT services have become a ubiquitous phenomenon. Companies worldwide are using the Web to provide personalized offerings and unique web experiences to their customers. While there is a lot of hype about delivering personalized services over the Web, little is known about the effectiveness of web personalization and the link between the IT artifact (the personalization agent) and the effects it exerts on a user’s information processing and decision making. To address the impact of personalized content, this article theoretically develops and empirically tests a model of web personalization. The model is grounded on social cognition and consumer research theories adapted to the peculiar features of web personalization. The influence of a personalization agent is mediated by two variables, content relevance and self reference. Hypotheses generated from the model are empirically tested in a laboratory experiment and a field study. The findings indicate that content relevance, self reference and goal specificity affect the attention, cognitive processes, and decisions of web users in various ways. Also, users are found to be receptive to personalized content and find it useful as a decision aid. Theoretical and practical implications of the findings are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2672&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Web personalization</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>processing goal</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>content relevance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>self reference</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>human computer interface</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2669</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:56Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Reconceptualizing Compatibility Beliefs</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Karahanna, Elena</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Agarwal, Ritu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Angst, Corey</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Theoretical and empirical research in technology acceptance, while acknowledging the importance of individual beliefs about the compatibility of a technology, has produced equivocal results.  This study focuses on further conceptual development of this important belief in technology acceptance.  Unlike much prior research that has focused on only a limited aspect of compatibility, we provide a more comprehensive conceptual definition that disaggregates the content of compatibility into four distinct and separable constructs: compatibility with preferred work style, compatibility with existing work practices, compatibility with prior experience, and compatibility with values.  We suggest that the form of the multidimensional compatibility construct is best modeled as a multivariate structural model.   Based on their conceptual definitions, we develop operational measures for the four compatibility variables.  We assess the nomological validity of our conceptualization by situating it within the technology acceptance model.  In contrast to prior research, which has regarded beliefs of compatibility as an independent antecedent of technology acceptance outcomes, we posit causal linkages not only among the four compatibility beliefs, but also between compatibility beliefs and usefulness, and ease of use.  We test our theoretical model with a field sample of 278 users of a customer relationship management system in the context of a large bank.  Scale validation indicates that the operational measures of compatibility developed in this study have acceptable psychometric properties, which support the existence of four distinct constructs.  Results largely support the theorized relationships.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2669&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2681</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Aligning Software Processes with Strategy</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Slaughter, Sandra A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Levine, Linda</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ramesh, Balasubramaniam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pries-Heje, Jan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Baskerville, Richard</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Although increasing evidence suggests that superior performance requires alignment between firms’ strategies and production processes, it is not known if such alignment is relevant for software development processes. This study breaks new ground by examining how firms align their software processes, products, and strategies in Internet application development. Drawing upon the literatures in strategy, operations management, and information systems, we identify four dimensions that influence alignment:  the business unit strategy, the level of product customization, the level of process customization, and the volume of customers. To examine how these dimensions are synchronized, we conducted detailed case studies of Internet application development in nine varied firms including both start-ups and established “brick and mortar” companies. Our analyses reveal that the firms in our study do use differing processes for Internet application development, and that many of the firms match their software process choices to product characteristics, customer volume, and business unit strategies. We develop concept maps for the firms that are in alignment to illustrate how managers configure specific product and process dimensions. We also offer potential explanations for why some firms are misaligned. Our study contributes to the information systems literature by providing detailed insights into how software processes are customized to complement different types of product requirements and strategies.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2681&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Software process</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>product–process matrix</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Internet application development</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>software development strategy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>competitive strategy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>contingency theory</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2683</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Effects of Personalization and Familiarity on Trust and Adoption of Recommendation Agents</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Komiak, Sherrie Y. X.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benbasat, Izak</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In the context of personalization technologies, such as Web-based product-brokering recommendation agents (RAs) in electronic commerce, existing technology acceptance theories need to be expanded to take into account not only the cognitive beliefs leading to adoption behavior, but also the affect elicited by the personalized nature of the technology. This study takes a trust-centered, cognitive and emotional balanced perspective to study RA adoption. Grounded on the theory of reasoned action, the IT adoption literature, and the trust literature, this study theoretically articulates and empirically examines the effects of perceived personalization and familiarity on cognitive trust and emotional trust in an RA, and the impact of cognitive trust and emotional trust on the intention to adopt the RA either as a decision aid or as a delegated agent.  An experiment was conducted using two commercial RAs. PLS analysis results provide empirical support for the proposed theoretical perspective. Perceived personalization significantly increases customers’ intention to adopt by increasing cognitive trust and emotional trust. Emotional trust plays an important role beyond cognitive trust in determining customers’ intention to adopt. Emotional trust fully mediates the impact of cognitive trust on the intention to adopt the RA as a delegated agent, while it only partially mediates the impact of cognitive trust on the intention to adopt the RA as a decision aid. Familiarity increases the intention to adopt through cognitive trust and emotional trust.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2683&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2684</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>So, Talk to Me:  The Effect of Explicit Goals on the Comprehension of Business Process Narratives</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kuechler, Bill</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vaishnavi, Vijay</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Unstructured data, most of it text-based and computer mediated, makes up a rapidly growing majority of the knowledge store of most organizations. Entire classes of information systems:  knowledge management systems and enterprise content management systems have emerged to monitor, manage and support decision making from this primarily textual data.   IS research has treated text as a unitary variable.  However, research from cognitive science strongly suggests that a deeper investigation of how text is comprehended would allow the development of more effective computer-based knowledge and communications systems.  Our research extends IS research on the effects of information presentation on decision making by investigating the attributes of text rather than comparing text to other information presentation modes such as graphs or numbers.  Our study also contributes to the sparse empirical IS research on problem formulation, the initial phase of decision making.  Informed by research on information presentation, decision making, and narrative comprehension we designed a series of experiments that demonstrate that the explicit inclusion of goal information for activities in narrative descriptions of problematic business processes increases overall comprehension, decision making confidence, and short and long term recall.  Based on our experimental findings we propose that augmenting text-based IS to elicit and saliently present explicit goal information would significantly enhance the decision support capability of these systems especially for rapid, ad hoc decisions about business process situations.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2684&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Decision support systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>decision making; human–computer interface</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>process comprehension</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2750</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Differential Use and Effect of Knowledge-Based System Explanations in Novice and Expert Judgment Decisions</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Arnold, Vicky</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Clark, Nicole</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Collier, Phillip A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Leech, Stewart A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sutton, Steve G.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Explanation facilities are considered essential in facilitating user interaction with knowledge-based systems (KBS). Research on explanation provision and the impact on KBS users has shown that the domain expertise affects the type of explanations selected by the user and the basis for seeking such explanations. The prior literature has been limited, however, by the use of simulated KBS that generally provide only feedback explanations (i.e., ex post to the recommendation of the KBS being presented to the user). The purpose of this study is to examine the way users with varying levels of expertise use alternative types of KBS explanations and the impact of that use on decision making. A total of 64 partner/manager-level and 82 senior/staff-level insolvency professionals participated in an experiment involving the use of a fully functioning KBS to complete a complex judgment task. In addition to feedback explanations, the KBS also provided feedforward explanations (i.e., general explanations during user input about the relationships between information cues in the KBS) and included definition type explanations (i.e., declarative-level knowledge). The results show that users were more likely to adhere to recommendation of the KBS when an explanation facility was available. Choice patterns in using explanations indicated that novices used feedforward explanations more than experts did, while experts were more likely than novices to use feedback explanations. Novices also used more declarative knowledge and initial problem solving type explanations, while experts used more procedural knowledge explanations. Finally, use of feedback explanations led to greater adherence to the KBS recommendation by experts—a condition that was even more prevalent as the use of feedback explanations increased. The results have several implications for the design and use of KBS in a professional decision making environment.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2750&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Explanations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>explanation use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge-based systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>expert systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>intelligent systems</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2682</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Knowledge Integration and Information Technology Project Performance</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Mitchell, Victoria L.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Successful product and process design depends on management’s ability to integrate fragmented pockets of specialized knowledge. This integrative capability has important implications for large-scale information technology projects. This article examines the relationship between timely project completion and two dimensions of management’s integrative capability:  access to external knowledge and internal knowledge integration. Measures of these two dimensions are used to predict on-time project completion, where completion is a function of the duration of IT-related project delays.  In a longitudinal study of 74 enterprise application integration projects in the medical sector, integrative capability was measured from the point of view of the CIO and a facility IT manager. Accounting for several project controls, our Cox regression results indicate both integrative dimensions significantly mitigate the duration of IT-related project delays, thus promoting timely project completion. The analysis also reveals the importance of taking management structure into consideration when studying IT phenomena in networked organizations.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss4/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2682&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>MIS management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>management structure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>integrative capabilities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>dynamic capabilities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>project delay</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2766</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>What Does it Take for a Journal to Be Global?</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2766&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2768</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Transformation of Open Source Software</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Fitzgerald, Brian</dc:creator>
<dc:description>A frequent characterization of open source software is the somewhat outdated, mythical one of a collective of supremely talented software hackers freely volunteering their services to produce uniformly high-quality software. I contend that the open source software phenomenon has metamorphosed into a more mainstream and commercially viable form, which I label as OSS 2.0. I illustrate this transformation using a framework of process and product factors, and discuss the shift in the application of the bazaar metaphor from the development process to the product delivery and support process. Overall the OSS 2.0 phenomenon is significantly different from its free software antecedent. Its emergence accentuates the fundamental alteration of the basic ground-rules in the software landscape, signifying the end of the proprietary-driven model that has prevailed for the past 20 years or so. Thus, a clear understanding of the characteristics of the emergent OSS 2.0 phenomenon is required to address key challenges for research and practice.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2768&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Open source software</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>free software</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS development</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2769</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Academic Data Collection in Electronic Environments:  Defining Acceptable Use of Internet Resources</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Allen, Gove N.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Burk, Dan L.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Davis, Gordon B.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Academic researchers access commercial websites to collect research data.  This research practice is likely to increase.  Is this appropriate?  Is this legal?  Such commercial websites are maintained to achieve business objectives; research access uses site resources for other purposes.  Website administrators may, therefore, deem academic data collection inappropriate.  Is there a process to make research access more open and acceptable to website owners and administrators?  These are significant issues.  This article clarifies the problems and suggests possible approaches to handle the issues with sensitivity and openness.  Research access to commercial websites may be manual (using a standard web browser) or automated (using automated data collection agents).  These approaches have different effects on websites.  Researchers using manual access tend to make a limited number of page requests because manual access is costly to perform.  Researchers using automated access methods can request large numbers of pages at a low cost.  Therefore, website administrators tend to view manual access and automated access very differently.  Because of the number of accesses and nonbusiness purpose, automated research requests for data are sometimes blocked by site administration using a variety of means (both technological and legal).  This paper details the pertinent legal issues including trespass, copyright violation, and breech of contract.  It also explains the nature of express and implied consent by site administration for research access.  Based on the issues presented, guidelines for researchers are proposed to reduce objections to research activities, to facilitate communication with website administration, and to achieve express or implied consent.  These include notification to website administration of intended automated research activity, description of the research project posted as a web page, and clear identification of automated requests for web pages.  In order to encourage good research practices with respect to automated data collection, suggestions are made with respect to disclosing methods used in research papers and for self regulation by academic associations.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2769&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Internet</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>automated data collection</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2771</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:58Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Nature of Theory in Information Systems</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gregor, Shirley</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The aim of this research essay is to examine the structural nature of theory in information systems.  Despite the importance of theory, questions relating to its form and structure are neglected in comparison with questions relating to epistemology.  The essay addresses issues of causality, explanation, prediction, and generalization that underlie an understanding of theory.  A taxonomy is proposed that classifies information systems theories with respect to the manner in which four central goals are addressed:  analysis, explanation, prediction, and prescription.  Five interrelated types of theory are distinguished:  (1) theory for analyzing, (2) theory for explaining, (3) theory for predicting, (4) theory for explaining and predicting, and (5) theory for design and action.  Examples illustrate the nature of each theory type.  The applicability of the taxonomy is demonstrated by classifying a sample of journal articles.  The paper contributes by showing that multiple views of theory exist and by exposing the assumptions underlying different viewpoints.  In addition, it is suggested that the type of theory under development can influence the choice of an epistemological approach.  Support is given for the legitimacy and value of each theory type.  The building of integrated bodies of theory that encompass all theory types is advocated.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2771&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>theory taxonomy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>theory structure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information systems discipline</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>philosophy of science</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>philosophy of social sciences</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>interpretivist theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>design theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>design science</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>explanation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>prediction</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>causality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>generalization</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2772</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Order Lead-Time Improvement Following Enterprise Information Technology Implementation:  An Empirical Study</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Cotteleer, Mark J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bendoly, Elliot</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper investigates the influence of enterprise systems implementation on operational performance.  The work extends the literature on enterprise systems by focusing on changes in process dynamics as a source for ongoing firm-level performance improvement.   A case discussion of Tristen Inc., a firm that implemented ERP and subsequently experienced benefits through gains to its continuous improvement efforts, is examined in light of theorized impacts of such implementations on process dynamics.  Analyses of longitudinal data suggest that performance along a key metric motivating the ERP initiative (i.e., order fulfillment lead-time) showed a significant improvement immediately after system deployment.  The data further suggest that the system implementation gave rise to an ongoing trend of performance improvement, in contrast to a stable performance trend prior to go-live.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2772&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Enterprise resource planning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>visibility</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>variability reduction</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>continuous improvement</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational learning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>empirical research</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2774</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Enhancing the Design of Web Navigation Systems:  The Influence of User Disorientation on Engagement and Performance</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Webster, Jane</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ahuja, Jaspreet S.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper draws on research from a wide literature base to develop a model relating Web navigation systems, disorientation, engagement, user performance, and intentions.  The model is tested in an experimental study examining the effects of one simple and two global navigation systems.  Although well-accepted design guidelines were followed for the first global navigation system, it was not superior to the simple system.  However, the second global navigation system resulted in lower disorientation than the simple system.  Based on the study’s results, two design guidelines to govern the development of future Web-based systems are suggested.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2774&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Disorientation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>lost</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>engagement</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>flow</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>World Wide Web</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Internet</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>design</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Web-based learning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic shopping</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Web navigation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>commercial Web site</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>efficiency</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>intentions</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2775</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Role of Espoused National Cultural Values in Technology Acceptance</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Srite, Mark</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karahanna, Elena</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Prior research has examined age, gender, experience, and voluntariness as the main moderators of beliefs on technology acceptance. This paper extends this line of research beyond these demographic and situational variables. Motivated by research that suggests that behavioral models do not universally hold across cultures, the paper identifies espoused national cultural values as an important set of individual difference moderators in technology acceptance. Building on research in psychological anthropology and cultural psychology that assesses cultural traits by personality tests at the individual level of analysis, we argue that individuals espouse national cultural values to differing degrees. These espoused national cultural values of masculinity/femininity, individualism/collectivism, power distance, and uncertainty avoidance are incorporated into an extended model of technology acceptance as moderators. We conducted two studies to test our model. Results indicated that, as hypothesized, social norms are stronger determinants of intended behavior for individuals who espouse feminine and high uncertainty avoidance cultural values.  Contrary to expectations, espoused masculinity/femininity values did not moderate the relationship between perceived usefulness and behavioral intention but, as expected, did moderate the relationship between perceived ease of use and behavioral intention.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2775&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Culture</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology acceptance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>adoption</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>TAM</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>masculinity/femininity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>individualism/collectivism</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>power distance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>uncertainty avoidance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>espoused cultural values</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2776</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:05:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Electronic Marketplaces and Price Transparency:  Strategy, Information Technology, and Success</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Soh, Christina</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Markus, M. L.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Goh, Kim H.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Electronic marketplaces (EMPs) are widely assumed to increase price transparency and hence lower product prices. Results of empirical studies have been mixed, with several studies showing that product prices have not decreased and others showing that prices have increased in some cases. One explanation is that sellers prefer not to join EMPs with high price transparency, leading highly price transparent EMPs to fail. Therefore, in order to be successful, EMPs might be expected to avoid high price transparency. But that strategy creates a catch-22 for EMPs on the buy side: Why would buyers want to join EMPs in the absence of price transparency and the benefit of lower prices? We argue that successful EMPs must provide compensatory benefits for sellers in the case of high price transparency and for buyers in the case of low price transparency.  To understand how EMPs could succeed, regardless of price transparency, we examined the relationships among EMP strategy, price transparency, and performance by analyzing all 19 EMPs that compete by selling a broad range of standard electronics components. We found that all EMPs pursuing a low cost strategy had high price transparency and performed poorly. All EMPs that performed well pursued strategies of differentiation, but, interestingly, not all successful EMPs avoided price transparency: Some EMPs succeeded despite enabling high price transparency. We therefore examined two differentiated EMPs in greater depth – one with high price transparency, the other with low price transparency – to show how they achieved strategic alignment of activities and resources and provided compensatory benefits for their customers.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2776&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Electronic marketplaces</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic market theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Internet</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>price transparency</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>strategic alignment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic components industry</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2757</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Reliability, Mindfulness, and Information Systems</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Butler, Brian S.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gray, Peter H.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In a world where information technology is both important and imperfect, organizations and individuals are faced with the ongoing challenge of determining how to use complex, fragile systems in dynamic contexts to achieve reliable outcomes.  While reliability is a central concern of information systems practitioners at many levels, there has been limited consideration in information systems scholarship of how firms and individuals create, manage, and use technology to attain reliability.  We propose that examining how individuals and organizations use information systems to reliably perform work will increase both the richness and relevance of IS research.  Drawing from studies of individual and organizational cognition, we examine the concept of mindfulness as a theoretical foundation for explaining efforts to achieve individual and organizational reliability in the face of complex technologies and surprising environments.  We then consider a variety of implications of mindfulness theories of reliability, in the form of alternative interpretations of existing knowledge and new directions for inquiry in the areas of IS operations, design, and management.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2757&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Mindfulness</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>reliability</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS operations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS design</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>resilience</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2758</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>PLS: A Silver Bullet?</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Marcoulides, George A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2758&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2759</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Firm Performance Impacts of Digitally Enabled Supply Chain Integration Capabilities</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Rai, Arun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patnayakuni, Ravi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patnayakuni, Nainika</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Best practice exemplars suggest that digital platforms play a critical role in managing supply chain activities and partnerships that generate performance gains for firms. However, there is limited academic investigation on how and why information technology can create performance gains for firms in a supply chain management (SCM) context.  Grant’s (1996) theoretical notion of higher-order capabilities and a hierarchy of capabilities has been used in recent information systems research by Barua et al. (2004), Sambamurthy et al. (2003), and Mithas et al. (2004) to reframe the conversation from the direct performance impacts of IT resources and investments, to how and why IT shapes higher-order process capabilities that create performance gains for firms. We draw on the emerging IT-enabled organizational capabilities perspective to suggest that firms that develop IT infrastructure integration for SCM and leverage it to create a higher-order supply chain integration capability, generate significant and sustainable performance gains. A research model is developed to investigate the hierarchy of IT-related capabilities and their impact on firm performance.  Data were collected from 110 supply chain and logistics managers in manufacturing and retail organizations. Our results suggest that integrated IT infrastructures enable firms to develop the higher-order capability of supply chain process integration. This capability enables firms to unbundle information flows from physical flows, and to share information with their supply chain partners to create information-based approaches for superior demand planning, for the staging and movement of physical products, and for streamlining voluminous and complex financial work processes. Furthermore, IT-enabled supply chain integration capability results in significant and sustained firm performance gains, especially in operational excellence and revenue growth. Managerial initiatives should be directed at developing an integrated IT infrastructure and leveraging it to create process capabilities for the integration of resource flows between a firm and its supply chain partners.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2759&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Supply chain process integration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT infrastructure integration for SCM</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>operational excellence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>revenue growth</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>firm performance</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2847</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Audio MP3</dc:title>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/x-cdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/context/misq/article/2847/type/native/viewcontent</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2777</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Professional Versus Political Contexts:  Institutional Mitigation of the Transaction Cost Heuristic in IS Outsourcing</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Miranda, Shaila M.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kim, Yong-Mi</dc:creator>
<dc:description>IS research has considered the outsourcing decision from the perspective of transaction cost economics (TCE) and institutional theory.  In this research, we consider how the appropriation of the logic of transaction cost economics is contingent on decision-makers’ institutional context.  The institutional contexts contrasted are professional versus political contexts.  In a survey of 214 city governments in the United States, we substantiate the existence of these two institutional contexts, a distinction that has been noted to extend into the private sector as well.    Subsequent analyses of the moderating effects of institutional context on the application of the TCE heuristic to the outsourcing decision revealed the following:  The institutional context moderated the impacts of “human frailty” conditions – of opportunism and bounded rationality – and of transaction frequency on outsourcing decisions.  In professional contexts, opportunism reduced outsourcing and frequency increased outsourcing; in political contexts, bounded rationality fostered outsourcing and frequency dissuaded outsourcing.  However, no institutional moderation was noted for the situational conditions of asset-specificity and uncertainty.  Instead, situational conditions were found to increase the incidence of outsourcing across both contexts.  Findings about the contingent effects of human frailty conditions augment our understanding of the outsourcing phenomenon by emphasizing that decision-makers’ attentiveness to the logic of transaction costs during outsourcing is shaped by their institutional context.  Findings with regard to situational conditions suggest a need for future research to consider the role of another contextual factor – resource munificence – in mitigating the effects of situational conditions on responses to transaction costs.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2777&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2778</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Information Technology and Pricing Decisions:  Price Adjustments in Online Computer Markets</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Oh, Wonseok</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lucas, Henry C., Jr</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Determining prices is a key management task for a merchant.  IT-enabled electronic markets facilitate price discovery by both buyers and sellers compared to traditional, physical markets. Recent research on electronic markets has revealed that IT has increased market transparency due to increased accessibility and availability of market information. However, what online sellers do in terms of strategic pricing decisions, in particular price adjustment behavior over time, has not been fully investigated. Due to the ease of making price changes, electronic sellers can execute a number of different pricing strategies, including setting the frequency and amount of price changes. We investigate the “opaque” side of electronic markets by exploring online sellers’ price adjustment patterns over time. More specifically, we identify four questions related to pricing decisions, which lead to hypotheses about how managers determine prices in electronic markets. The paper tests the hypotheses with data from the online computer commodity market.  We found, through a simulation analysis, that this market exhibits synchronized price changes, not random changes that are frequently found in traditional markets. Interestingly, small price increases occur more frequently than decreases, while the frequency of price adjustment is significantly associated with a product’s price dispersion.  A ranking analysis suggests that online sellers change their price strategies frequently, which makes it difficult for consumers to respond appropriately. The paper discusses the implications of our findings for management and for future research on market transparency and strategic pricing in electronic markets.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss3/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2778&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Market transparency</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>strategic pricing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>price adjustment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information technology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic markets</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>computer simulations</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2763</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Plant Information Systems, Manufacturing Capabilities and Plant Performance</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Banker, Rajiv D.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bardhan, Indranil R.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chang, Hsihui</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lin, Shu</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Firms have been investing over $5 billion a year in recent years on new information technology and software in their manufacturing plants.  In this study, we develop a conceptual model based on the theory of dynamic capabilities to study how manufacturing plants realize improvements in plant performance by leveraging plant information systems to enable implementation of advanced manufacturing capabilities.  We develop hypotheses about relationships between information systems, their impact on manufacturing practices, and the overall impact on plant performance.  Analysis of survey data from 1,077 U.S. manufacturing plants provides empirical support for the dynamic capabilities model and suggests that manufacturing capabilities mediate the impact of information systems on plant performance.  Our results underscore the importance of manufacturing and organizational capabilities in studying the impact of IT on manufacturing plant productivity, and provide a sharper theoretical lens to evaluate their impact.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2763&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Manufacturing capabilities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>resource planning systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic data interchange</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>just-in-time manufacturing</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2762</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Impact of Ideology on Effectiveness in Open Source Software Development Teams</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Stewart, Katherine J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gosain, Sanjay</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The emerging work on understanding open source software has questioned what leads to effectiveness in OSS development teams in the absence of formal controls, and it has pointed to the importance of ideology.  This paper develops a framework of the OSS community ideology (including specific norms, beliefs, and values) and a theoretical model to show how adherence to components of the ideology impacts effectiveness in OSS teams.  The model is based on the idea that the tenets of the OSS ideology motivate behaviors that enhance cognitive trust and communication quality and encourage identification with the project team, which enhances affective trust.  Trust and communication in turn impact OSS team effectiveness.  The research considers two kinds of effectiveness in OSS teams:  the attraction and retention of developer input and the generation of project outputs. Hypotheses regarding antecedents to each are developed. Hypotheses are tested using survey and objective data on OSS projects.  Results support the main thesis that OSS team members’ adherence to the tenets of the OSS community ideology impacts OSS team effectiveness and reveal that different components impact effectiveness in different ways.  Of particular interest is the finding that adherence to some ideological components was beneficial to the effectiveness of the team in terms of attracting and retaining input, but detrimental to the output of the team.  Theoretical and practical implications are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2762&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Open source software</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>trust</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ideology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>communication</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>virtual teams</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2760</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>An Empirical Analysis of the Value of Complete Information for eCRM Models</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Padmanabhan, Balaji</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zheng, Zhiqiang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kimbrough, Steven O.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Due to the vast amount of user data tracked online, the use of data-based analytical methods is becoming increasingly common for e-businesses.  Recently the term analytical eCRM has been used to refer to the use of such methods in the online world.  A characteristic of most of the current approaches in eCRM is that they use data collected about users’ activities at a single site only and, as we argue in this paper, this can present an incomplete picture of user activity.  However, it is possible to obtain a complete picture of user activity from across-site data on users.  Such data is expensive, but can be obtained by firms directly from their users or from market data vendors.  A critical question is whether such data is worth obtaining, an issue that little prior research has addressed.  In this paper, using a data mining approach, we present an empirical analysis of the modeling benefits that can be obtained by having complete information.  Our results suggest that the magnitudes of gains that can be obtained from complete data range from a few percentage points to 50 percent, depending on the problem for which it is used and the performance metrics considered.  Qualitatively we find that variables related to customer loyalty and browsing intensity are particularly important and these variables are difficult to derive from data collected at a single site.  More importantly, we find that a firm has to collect a reasonably large amount of complete data before any benefits can be reaped and caution against acquiring too little data.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2760&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Data mining</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>incomplete data</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information value</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>eCRM</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2761</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Effects of State-Based and Event-Based Data Representations on User Performance in Query Formulation Tasks</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Allen, Gove N.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>March, Salvatore T.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Ad hoc query formulation is an important task in effectively utilizing organizational data resources.  To facilitate this task, managers and casual end-users are commonly presented with database views expressly constructed for their use.  Differences in the way in which things, states, and events are represented in such views can affect a user’s ability to understand the database, potentially leading to different levels of performance (i.e., accuracy, confidence, and prediction of the accuracy of their queries).  An experiment was conducted over the Internet involving 342 subjects from 6 universities in North America and Europe to investigate these effects.  When presented with an event-based view, subjects expressing low or very low comfort levels in reading entity-relationship diagrams expressed confidence that better predicted query accuracy although there were no significant differences in actual query accuracy or level of confidence expressed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2761&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Query formulation performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>event-based</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>state-based</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>artifact-based</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>data models</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>database user view</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sense-making</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>E-R diagram</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2764</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Managing Peer-to-Peer Conflicts in Disruptive Information Technology Innovations:  The Case of Software Reuse</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sherif, Karma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zmud, Robert W.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Browne, Glenn J.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>We examine the case of software reuse as a disruptive information technology innovation (i.e., one that requires changes in the architecture of work processes) in software development organizations.  Using theories of conflict, coordination, and learning, we develop a model to explain peer-to-peer conflicts that are likely to accompany the introduction of disruptive technologies and how appropriately devised managerial interventions (e.g., coordination mechanisms and organizational learning practices) can lessen these conflicts.  A study of software reuse programs in four organizations was conducted to assess the validity of the model.  Qualitative and quantitative analyses of the data obtained showed that companies that had implemented such managerial interventions experienced greater success with their software reuse programs.  Implications for theory and practice are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2764&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Disruptive IT innovations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>software reuse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>goal conflict</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>coordination mechanisms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational learning</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2747</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Personalization Privacy Paradox:  An Empirical Evaluation of Information Transparency and the Willingeness to be Profiled Online for Personalization</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Awad, Neveen Farag</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Krishnan, M. S.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Firms today use information about customers to improve service and design customized offerings. To do this successfully, however, firms must collect consumer information. This study enhances awareness about a central paradox for firms investing in personalization; namely, that consumers who value information transparency are also less likely to participate in personalization.  We examine the relationship between information technology features, specifically information transparency features, and consumer willingness to share information for online personalization.  Based on a survey of over 400 online consumers, we examine the question of whether customer perceived information transparency is associated with consumer willingness to be profiled online.  Our results indicate that customers who desire greater information transparency are less willing to be profiled.  This result poses a dilemma for firms, as the consumers that value information transparency features most are also the consumers who are less willing to be profiled online.  In order to manage this dilemma, we suggest that firms adopt a strategy of providing features that address the needs of consumers who are more willing to partake in personalization, therefore accepting that the privacy sensitive minority of consumers are unwilling to participate in personalization, despite additional privacy features.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2747&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Online privacy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information transparency</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>web site features</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online experience</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>consumer privacy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online personalization</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online information sharing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>empirical studies of information systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business value of information systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information sharing practices</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2746</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Research Standards for Promotion and Tenure in Information Systems1</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Dennis, Alan R.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Valacich, Joseph S.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fuller, Mark A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Schneider, Christoph</dc:creator>
<dc:description>What constitutes excellence in information systems research for promotion and tenure?  This is a question that is regularly addressed by members of promotion and tenure committees and those called upon to write external letters.  While there are many elements to this question, one major element is the quality and quantity of an individual’s research publications.  An informal survey of senior Information Systems faculty members at 49 leading U.S. and Canadian universities found 86 percent to expect three or more articles in elite journals.  In contrast, an analysis of publication performance of Ph.D. graduates between the years of 1992 and 2004 found that approximately three individuals in each graduating year of Ph.D.s (about 2 percent) published 3 or more articles in a set of 20 elite journals within 6 years of graduation.  Only 15 individuals from each graduating year (11 percent) published one or more articles.  As a discipline, we publish elite journal articles at a lower rate than Accounting, yet our promotion and tenure standards are higher, similar to those of Management, Marketing, and Finance.  Thus, there is a growing divergence between research performance and research standards within the Information Systems discipline.  As such, unless we make major changes, these differences will perpetuate a vicious cycle of increasing faculty turnover, declining influence on university affairs, and lower research productivity.  We believe that we must act now to create a new future, and offer recommendations that focus on the use of more appropriate standards for promotion and tenure and ways to increase the number of articles published.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2746&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Tenure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>promotion</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>publishing standards</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2765</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>A Review of Culture in Information Systems Research: Toward a Theory of Information Technology Culture Conflict</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Leidner, Dorothy E.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kayworth, Timothy</dc:creator>
<dc:description>An understanding of culture is important to the study of information technologies in that culture at various levels, including national, organizational, and group, can influence the successful implementation and use of information technology.  Culture also plays a role in managerial processes that may directly, or indirectly, influence IT.  Culture is a challenging variable to research, in part because of the multiple divergent definitions and measures of culture.  Notwithstanding, a wide body of literature has emerged that sheds light on the relationship of IT and culture.  This paper sets out to provide a review of this literature in order to lend insights into our understanding of the linkages between IT and culture. We begin by conceptualizing culture and laying the groundwork for a values-based approach to the examination of IT and culture. Using this approach, we then provide a comprehensive review of the organizational and cross-cultural IT literature that conceptually links these two traditionally separate streams of research. From our analysis, we develop six themes of IT culture research emphasizing culture’s impact on IT, IT’s impact on culture, and IT culture. Building upon these themes, we then develop a theory of IT, values, and conflict.  Based upon the theory, we develop propositions concerning three types of cultural conflict and the results of these conflicts.  Ultimately, the theory suggests that the reconciliation of these conflicts results in a reorientation of values. We conclude with the particular research challenges posed in this line of inquiry.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss2/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2765&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>National culture</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational culture</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT values</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2748</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Role of Cognitive Fit in the Relationship between Software Comprehension and Modification</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Shaft, Teresa M.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vessey, Iris</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Although there is a long tradition of empirical studies of software developers, few studies have focused on software maintenance.  Prior work is predicated on the belief that higher levels of comprehension are associated with higher levels of performance on modification tasks.  This study provides a more complete understanding of the relationship between software comprehension and modification.  We conceptualize software maintenance as interlinking comprehension and modification, and argue that the relationship between the two is moderated by cognitive fit.  Specifically, cognitive fit exists when the software maintainer’s dominant mental representation of the software and their mental representation of the modification task emphasize the same type of knowledge.  We hypothesize that when cognitive fit exists, greater improvements in comprehension are associated with higher levels of performance on a modification task.  When cognitive fit does not exist, however, the software maintainer’s mental representations of the software and of the modification task do not emphasize the same type of knowledge, which may mean that attention is devoted to comprehension at the expense of modification, resulting in lower performance on the modification task.  In these circumstances, comprehension and modification tasks may interfere with each other, an effect known as dual-task interference.  We therefore hypothesize that performance on a modification task is moderated by the fit between the mental representation of the software and that of the modification task.   We tested our theory by varying cognitive fit to create matched and mis-matched conditions in a single experiment that used IT professionals as subjects.  Our findings support our theory:  cognitive fit moderates the relationship between comprehension and modification.  Specifically, changes in software comprehension and modification performance are positively related when cognitive fit exists and negatively related when cognitive fit does not exist.  Our findings demonstrate the need to examine more complex relationships among the numerous types of tasks involved in software development rather than examining software comprehension alone.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2748&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Cognitive fit</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>software modification</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>software comprehension</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>dual-task interference</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2749</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Performance Effects of Information Technology Synergies in Multibusiness Firms</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Tanriverdi, Hüseyin</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Unlike technologies that are applicable in a few specific industries, information technologies have a wide range of applicability across almost all industries. The fundamental principles of good IT management are also applicable in many industries. Thus, firms whose business units operate in different industries have an opportunity to exploit cross-unit IT synergies by applying their IT resources and management processes across multiple units. This study examines sources of cross-unit IT synergy and the conditions under which cross-unit IT synergies improve the performance of multibusiness firms. Building on the resource-based view (RBV) of diversification and the economic theory of complementarities, the study identifies the relatedness and complementarity of IT resources as two major sources of cross-unit IT synergy. It argues that IT relatedness—the use of common IT infrastructure technologies and common IT management processes across business units—creates sub-additive cost synergies, whereas complementarities among IT infrastructure technologies and IT management processes create super-additive value synergies. In a sample of 356 multibusiness Fortune1000 firms, the study finds that sub-additive cost synergies arising from the use of related IT resources or management processes do not have any effects on corporate performance, whereas the super-additive value synergies arising from the use of a complementary set of IT resources and management processes have significant effects on corporate performance. The diversification level of the firm moderates the relationship between IT synergies and corporate performance. As the diversification level increases, the performance effects of IT synergies remain positive, but they become weaker. The IT governance mode of the firm (centralized, decentralized, hybrid) does not make a difference in the performance effects of IT synergies.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2749&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Corporate performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>multibusiness firm</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>synergy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>relatedness</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>complementarity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>diversification</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>it governance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>coordination</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>survey</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>second-order construct</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2752</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Unraveling the Temporal Fabric of Knowledge Conversion: A Model of Media Selection and Use</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Massey, Anne P.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Montoya-Weiss, Mitzi M.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>We draw from and extend Nonaka’s (1994) theory of knowledge creation to develop a model of media selection and use in the knowledge conversion (KC) process. KC is a process wherein an individual is affected by the experiences of another. The outcomes of KC—transferred and transformed knowledge—hinge on the development of understanding. The KC process is enabled via various communicative and non-communicative media. Because the KC process occurs over time, it possesses a temporal fabric or structure. We explore the practical realities of KC as a dynamic, time- and experience-dependent process. We consider how the temporal fabric of KC creates an evolving reciprocal relationship among perceived media utility, selection, and use of media, as well as switching and/or combining media. We propose and discuss two key factors as determinants of perceived media utility use in the KC process: (1) the temporal behavior of individuals engaged in the KC process and (2) individual and joint experience-based factors. We also discuss the role of contextual factors as antecedents. Finally, we offer and illustrate two primary temporal structures for KC media selection and use: (1) monophasic, wherein KC participants use a single medium at a time, and (2) polyphasic, wherein KC participants deploy multiple media simultaneously. We conclude with a discussion of the implications for the design of KC-enabling systems and directions for future research.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2752&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge conversion</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>individual temporal behavior</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>media utility</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>monophasic and polyphasic temporal structures</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2754</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Incorporating Software Agents into Supply Chains:  Experimental Investigation with a Procurement Task</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Nissen, Mark E.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sengupta, Kishore</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Recently, researchers have begun investigating an emerging, technology-enabled innovation that involves the use of intelligent software agents in enterprise supply chains. Software agents combine and integrate capabilities of several information technology classes in a novel manner that enables supply chain management and decision making in modes not supported previously by IT and not reported previously in the information systems literature. Indeed, federations and swarms of software agents today are moving the boundaries of computer-aided decision making more generally. Such moving boundaries highlight promising new opportunities for competitive advantage in business, in addition to novel theoretical insights. But they also call for shifting research thrusts in information systems.  The stream of research associated with this article is taking some first steps to address such issues by examining experimentally the capabilities, limitations, and boundaries of agent technology for computer-based decision support and automation in the procurement domain. Procurement represents an area of particular potential for agent-based process innovation, as well as reflecting some of the greatest technological advances in terms of agents emerging from the laboratory. Procurement is imbued with considerable ambiguity in its task environment, ambiguity that presents a fundamental limitation to IT-based automation of decision making and knowledge work. By investigating the comparative performance of human and software agents across varying levels of ambiguity in the procurement domain, the experimentation described in this article helps to elucidate some new boundaries of computer-based decision making quite broadly. We seek in particular to learn from this domain and to help inform computer-based decision making, agent technological design, and IS research more generally.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2754&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Agents</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>artificial intelligence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>behavioral decision theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>computer-aided decision making</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>human performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>procurement; supply chain management</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2753</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Understanding and Predicting Electronic Commerce Adoption:  An Extension of the Theory of Planned Behavior</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pavlou, Paul A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fygenson, Mendel</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper extends Ajzen’s (1991) theory of planned behavior (TPB) to explain and predict the process of e-commerce adoption by consumers. The process is captured through two online consumer behaviors: (1) getting information and (2) purchasing a product from a Web vendor. First, we simultaneously model the association between these two contingent online behaviors and their respective intentions by appealing to consumer behavior theories and the theory of implementation intentions, respectively. Second, following TPB, we derive for each behavior its intention, attitude, subjective norm, and perceived behavioral control (PBC). Third, we elicit and test a comprehensive set of salient beliefs for each behavior.   A longitudinal study with online consumers supports the proposed e-commerce adoption model, validating the predictive power of TPB and the proposed conceptualization of PBC as a higher-order factor formed by self-efficacy and controllability. Our findings stress the importance of trust and technology adoption variables (perceived usefulness and ease of use) as salient beliefs for predicting e-commerce adoption, justifying the integration of trust and technology adoption variables within the TPB framework. In addition, technological characteristics (download delay, Website navigability, and information protection), consumer skills, time and monetary resources, and product characteristics (product diagnosticity and product value) add to the explanatory and predictive power of our model. Implications for Information Systems, e-commerce, TPB, and the study of trust are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2753&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Theory of planned behavior</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>perceived behavioral control</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>self-efficacy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>controllability</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology adoption</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology acceptance model</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>trust</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>consumer behavior</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2755</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Ethical Decision Making in Software Piracy:  Initial Development and Test of a Four-Component Model</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Moores, Trevor T.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cha-Jan Chang, Jerry</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Software piracy costs the software industry billions of dollars each year.  To better understand piracy, we propose a model of ethical decision making that is an adaptation of the four-component model of morality.  This model defines four internal processes that result in external moral behavior:  recognition, judgment, intention, and behavior.  We test our model with a sample of Information Systems students in Hong Kong who provided measures of self-reported behavior regarding levels of buying and using pirated software.  Using partial least squares, we investigated the causal pathways of the model and the effects of age and gender.  We find that use is determined by buying, buying is determined by intention, and intention is determined by judgment.  Although respondents recognized software piracy as an infringement of intellectual property rights, this fact did not affect their judgment of the morality of the act.  We also find significant differences in the ethical decision-making process based on age but only limited differences based on gender.  We discuss the implications of these results, including the development of a professional ethics program</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2755&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Ethics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>morality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ethical decision-making</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>moral reasoning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ethical scenarios</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>intellectual property rights</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>software piracy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>age</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>gender</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2779</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Necessary Changes</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2779&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2448</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Absorptive Capacity Configurations in Supply Chains: Gearing for Partner-Enabled Market Knowledge Creation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Malhotra, Arvind</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gosain, Sanjay</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>El Sawy, Omar A.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-12-31T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2448&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2738</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Taking Industry Seriously in Information Systems Research</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Chiasson, Mike W.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Davidson, Elizabeth</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In this essay, we argue that industry receives little attention in IS research and theory, despite its increasingly important influence on information systems (IS) activities.  This is evident both in the narrow range of industries examined in IS research and the infrequent consideration of industry in theory.  We base these observations on an analysis of IS publications in two top-tier journals (MIS Quarterly and Information Systems Research) over eight years.  Drawing from institutional theory, we consider various ways industry can be addressed and assess how industry influences IS activities.  We conclude that industry provides an important contextual “space” to build new IS theory and to evaluate the boundaries of existing IS theory.  We outline a range of strategies for incorporating industry into IS research.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2738&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information systems theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>institutional theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>industry content</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2739</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Zones of Tolerance:  Alternative Scales for Measuring Information Systems Service Quality</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kettinger, William J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lee, Choong C.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The expectation norm of comparison for Information Systems SERVQUAL has been challenged on both conceptual and empirical grounds, drawing into question the instrument’s practical value.  To address the criticism that the original IS SERVQUAL’s expectation measure is ambiguous, we test a new set of scales that posits that service expectations exist at two levels which IS customers use as a basis to assess IS service quality:  (1) desired service:  the level of IS service desired, and (2) adequate service:  the minimum level of IS service customers are willing to accept.  Defining these two levels is a zone of tolerance (ZOT) that represents the range of IS service performance a customer would consider satisfactory. In other words, IS customer service expectations are characterized by a range of levels, rather than a single expectation point. This research note adapts the ZOT and the generic operational definition from marketing to the IS field, assessing its psychometric properties. Our findings conclude that the instrument shows validity of a four-dimension IS ZOT SERVQUAL measure for desired, adequate, and perceived service quality levels, identifying 18 commonly applicable question items. This measure addresses past criticism while offering a practical diagnostic tool.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2739&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IS service quality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>zones of tolerance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>SERVQUAL</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>evaluation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>user expectations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information services function</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2740</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Information Technology and the Performance of the Customer Service Process:  A Resource-Based Analysis</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ray, Gautam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Muhanna, Waleed A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Barney, Jay B.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Delivering quality customer service has emerged as a strategic imperative, one that is increasingly tied to a firm’s information technology resources and capabilities. This paper presents an empirical study that examines the extent to which IT impacts customer service.  More specifically, this study investigates the differential effects of various IT resources and capabilities on the performance of the customer service process across firms that compete in the North American life and health insurance industry.  The paper builds on (1) information systems work that suggests that the effects of IT are best documented at the level of processes within a firm, (2) information systems work that suggests that the performance effects of IT are likely to be contingent in nature, and (3) developments in the resource-based view which describes the kinds of IT resources and capabilities that are likely to enable a process in one firm to outperform the same process in competing firms. The findings suggest that tacit, socially complex, firm-specific resources explain variation in process performance across firms and that IT resources and capabilities without these attributes do not. Of particular interest to IS scholars, it is found that shared knowledge between IT and customer service units—an important driver of how IT is implemented and used in the customer service process—is a key IT capability that affects customer service process performance and moderates the impacts of explicit IT resources such as the generic information technologies used in the process and IT spending, which—consistent with resource-based predictions—were not found to be directly and positively associated with relative process performance. The implications of the findings for research and practice are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2740&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT resources and capabilities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>shared knowledge</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>resource-based theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business processes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>process performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business value of IT</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2450</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:04Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Behavioral Intention Formation in Knowledge Sharing: Examining the Roles of Extrinsic Motivators, Social-Psychological Forces, and Organizational Climate</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Bock, Gee-Woo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zmud, Robert W.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kim, Young-Gul</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lee, Jae-Nam</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-12-31T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2450&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2743</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Intellectual Property Rights and Cannibalization in Information Technology Outsourcing Contracts</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Walden, Eric A.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper examines the question of how intellectual property rights in the software created during information technology outsourcing relationships should be divided.  This paper expands on the property rights approach developed by Grossman, Hart, and Moore by recognizing that, with respect to software, it is possible to separate excludability rights from usability rights.  These rights are modeled and the contractually optimal distribution is determined.  This model is then modified to account for the possibility of cannibalization of the client’s benefit when multiple others are allowed use of the software.  The results show that the best contractual structure depends strongly on the environment.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2743&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Contracts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>outsourcing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>economic models</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>interorganizational relationships</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2741</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Managing Client Dialogues During Information Systems Design to Facilitate Client Learning</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Majchrzak, Ann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Beath, Cynthia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lim, Ricardo A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chin, Wynne W.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>It has long been recognized that client learning is an important factor in the successful development of information systems.  While there is little question that clients should learn, there is less clarity about how best to facilitate client learning during developer-client meetings.  In this study, we suggest that a cooperative learning strategy called collaborative elaboration developed by educational psychologists provides a theoretical and practical basis for stimulating client learning during an IS design process. The problem with assessing the effects of collaborative elaboration, however, is in controlling for the many other factors that might affect client learning and outcomes of an IS design phase.  In a unique research opportunity, we were able to measure the use of collaborative elaboration among 85 developers and clients involved in 17 projects over a semester-long IS design process.  The projects were homogeneous with respect to key contextual variables.  Our PLS analysis suggested that teams using more collaborative elaboration had more client learning and teams with more client learning achieved better IS design phase outcomes.  This suggests that theories about collaborative elaboration have significant potential for helping IS researchers identify new approaches for stimulating client learning early in the IS design process.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2741&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2742</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Effects of Virtual Reality on Consumer Learning:  An Empirical Investigation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Suh, Kil-Soo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lee, Young Eun</dc:creator>
<dc:description>As competition in business-to-consumer electronic commerce becomes fiercer, Web-based stores are attempting to attract consumers’ attention by exploiting state-of-the-art technologies. Virtual reality (VR) on the Internet has recently been gaining prominence because it enables consumers to experience products realistically over the Internet, thereby mitigating the problems associated with consumers’ lack of physical contact with products. However, while the employment of  has increased in B2C e-commerce, its impact has not been explored extensively by research in the Information Systems field.  The present study investigates whether and under what circumstances  enhances consumer learning about products. In general,  enables consumers to learn about products thoroughly by providing high-quality, three-dimensional images of products, interactivity with the products, and increased telepresence. In addition, congruent with the theory of cognitive fit, the effects of  are more pronounced when it exhibits products whose salient attributes are completely apparent through visual and auditory cues (because most VR on desktop computers uses only those two sensory modalities to deliver information). Based on these attributes, we distinguish between two types of products—virtually high experiential (VHE) and virtually low experiential (VLE)—in terms of the sensory modalities that are used and required for product inspection. Hypotheses arising from the distinctions expressed by these terms were tested via a laboratory experiment. The results support the predictions that VR interfaces increase overall consumer learning about products and that these effects extend to VHE products more significantly than to VLE products.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2742&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Virtual reality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>consumer learning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>interface design in e-commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cognitive fit</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2744</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:06Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The History of Texaco&#39;s Corporate Information Technology Function:  A General Systems Theoretical Interpretation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Porra, Jaana</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hirschheim, Rudy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Parks, Michael S.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>We attempt to use general systems theory (GST) to understand why resources at Texaco’s corporate information technology function consistently did not match its task during its 40-year lifetime. Our interpretation uses mechanistic, organic, and colonial systems metaphors, each with three components. The first is an analysis of a management action system made up of organizational indicators such as Texaco’s revenues, profits, employee numbers, IT budgets, and IT personnel numbers. The second is a narrative of performance versus resource needs in Texaco IT function, which shows a gap between IT&#39;s resources and its expanding responsibilities. The third is a management-perception system, which offers reasons why top management continually misinterpreted IT’s performance as inferior. Our results show that the mechanistic, organic, and colonial interpretations converge. In addition, our GST-based interpretations show how top management might have remedied the situation.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2744&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Systems theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mechanistic</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organic and colonial systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>historical research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>interpretive research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT function success factors</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT function failure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>longitudinal study</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2829</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>EDITOR’S COMMENTS Volume 29 Iss. 4</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2829&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2831</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Subject Index for Volume 29</dc:title>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2831&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2832</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Author Index for Volume 29</dc:title>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2832&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2833</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Reviewer Acknowledgments</dc:title>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/13</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2833&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2745</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>IT-Dependent Strategic Initiatives and Sustained Competitive Advantage:  A Review and Synthesis of the Literature</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Piccoli, Gabriele</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ives, Blake</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The role of information systems in the creation and appropriation of economic value has a long tradition of research, within which falls the literature on the sustainability of IT-dependent competitive advantage. In this article, we formally define the notion of IT-dependent strategic initiative and use it to frame a review of the literature on the sustainability of competitive advantage rooted in information systems use. We offer a framework that articulates both the dynamic approach to IT-dependent strategic advantage currently receiving attention in the literature and the underlying drivers of sustainability. This framework models how and why the characteristics of the IT-dependent strategic initiative enable sustained competitive advantage, and how the determinants of sustainability are developed and strengthened over time. This explanation facilitates the pre-implementation analysis of planned initiatives by innovators, as well as the post-implementation evaluation of existing initiatives so as to identify the basis of their sustainability.  In carrying out this study, we examined the interdisciplinary literature on strategic information systems. Using a structured methodology, we reviewed the titles and abstracts of 648 articles drawn from information systems, strategic management, and marketing literature. We then examined and individually coded a relevant subset of 117 articles. The literature has identified four barriers to erosion of competitive advantage for IT-dependent strategic initiatives and has surfaced the structural determinants of their magnitude. Previous work has also begun to theorize about the process by which these barriers to erosion evolve over time. Our review reveals that significant exploratory research and theoretical development have occurred in this area, but there is a paucity of research providing rigorous tests of theoretical propositions.    Our work makes three principal contributions. First, it formalizes the definition of IT-dependent strategic initiative. Second, it organizes the extant interdisciplinary research around an integrative framework that should prove useful to both research and practice. This framework offers an explanation of how and why IT-dependent strategic initiatives contribute to sustained competitive advantage, and explains the process by which they evolve over time. Finally, our review and analysis of the literature offers the basis for future research directions.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2745&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Strategic information systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sustainable competitive advantage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>competitive advantage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>strategic agility</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT-dependent strategic initiatives</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2830</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>MIS Quarterly ERRATA NOTES</dc:title>
<dc:creator>DeGross, Janice I.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss4/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2830&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2730</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Information Systems Identity Crisis:  Focusing on High-Visibility and High-Impact Research</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Agarwal, Ritu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lucas Jr., Henry C.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper presents an alternative view of the Information Systems identity crisis described recently by Benbasat and Zmud (2003).  We agree with many of their observations, but we are concerned with their prescription for IS research.  We critique their discussion of errors of inclusion and exclusion in IS research and highlight the potential misinterpretations that are possible from a literal reading of their comments.  Our conclusion is that following Benbasat and Zmud’s nomological net will result in a micro focus for IS research.  The results of such a focus are potentially dangerous for the field.  They could result in the elimination of IS from many academic programs.  We present an alternative set of heuristics that can be used to assess what lies within the domain of IS scholarship.  We argue that the IS community has a powerful story to tell about the transformational impact of information technology.  We believe that a significant portion of our research should be macro studies of the impact of IT.  It is important for academic colleagues, deans, and managers to understand the transformational power of the technology.  As IS researchers with deep knowledge of the underlying artifact, we are best positioned to do such research.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2730&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IS identity crisis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>transformational impact of IT</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>macro studies of IT</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2734</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>A Multilevel Model of Resistance to Information Technology Implementation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Lapointe, Liette</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rivard, Suzanne</dc:creator>
<dc:description>To better explain resistance to information technology implementation, we used a multilevel, longitudinal approach. We first assessed extant models of resistance to IT. Using semantic analysis, we identified five basic components of resistance:  behaviors, object, subject, threats, and initial conditions. We further examined extant models to (1) carry out a preliminary specification of the nature of the relationships between these components and (2) refine our understanding of the multilevel nature of the phenomenon. Using analytic induction, we examined data from three case studies of clinical information systems implementations in hospital settings, focusing on physicians’ resistance behaviors.  The resulting mixed-determinants model suggests that group resistance behaviors vary during implementation. When a system is introduced, users in a group will first assess it in terms of the interplay between its features and individual and/or organizational-level initial conditions.  They then make projections about the consequences of its use. If expected consequences are threatening, resistance behaviors will result. During implementation, should some trigger occur to either modify or activate an initial condition involving the balance of power between the group and other user groups, it will also modify the object of resistance, from system to system significance. If the relevant initial conditions pertain to the power of the resisting group vis-à-vis the system advocates, the object of resistance will also be modified, from system significance to system advocates. Resistance behaviors will follow if threats are perceived from the interaction between the object of resistance and initial conditions. We also found that the bottom-up process by which group resistance behaviors emerge from individual behaviors is not the same in early versus late implementation. In early implementation, the emergence process is one of compilation, described as a combination of independent, individual behaviors. In later stages of implementation, if group level initial conditions have become active, the emergence process is one of composition, described as the convergence of individual behaviors.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2734&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>User resistance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information technology implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information system implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>longitudinal perspective</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>multilevel approach</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>resistance behaviors</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>semantic analysis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>case study</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2735</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Understanding User Responses to Information Technology:  A Coping Model of User Adaptation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Beaudry, Anne</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pinsonneault, Alain</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper defines user adaptation as the cognitive and behavioral efforts performed by users to cope with significant IT events that occur in their work environment. Drawing on Coping Theory, we posit that users choose different adaptation strategies based on a combination of primary appraisal (i.e. a user’s assessment of the expected consequences of an IT event) and secondary appraisal (i.e. a user’s assessment of his/her control over the situation). On that basis, we identify four adaptation strategies (Benefits Maximizing, Benefits Satisficing, Disturbance Handling, and Self-Preservation) which are hypothesized to result in three different individual-level outcomes: restoring emotional stability, minimizing the perceived threats of the technology, and improving user effectiveness and efficiency. A study of the adaptation behaviors of six account managers in two large North American banks provides preliminary support for our model. By explaining adaptation patterns based on users’ initial appraisal and subsequent responses to an IT event, our model offers predictive power while retaining an agency view of user adaptation. Also, by focusing on user cognitive and behavioral adaptation responses related to the technology, the work system, and the self, our model accounts for a wide range of user behaviors such as technology appropriation, avoidance, and resistance.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2735&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Coping theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>user adaptation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT appropriation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>individual performance</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2736</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>A Comprehensive Conceputalization of the Post-Adoptive Behaviors Associated with IT-Enabled Work Systems</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Jasperson, &#39;Jon (Sean)</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carter, Pamela E.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zmud, Robert W.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>For the last 25 years, organizations have invested heavily in information technology (IT) to support their work processes. In today’s organizations, intra- and inter-organizational work systems are increasingly IT-enabled. Available evidence, however, suggests the functional potential of these installed IT applications is underutilized. Most IT users apply a narrow band of features, operate at low levels of feature use, and rarely initiate extensions of the available features. We argue that organizations need aggressive tactics to encourage users to expand their use of installed IT-enabled work systems.  This article strives to accomplish three primary research objectives. First, we offer a comprehensive research model aimed both at coalescing existing research on post-adoptive IT use behaviors and at directing future research on those factors that influence users to (continuously) exploit and extend the functionality built into IT applications. Second, in developing this comprehensive research model, we provide a window (for researchers across a variety of scientific disciplines interested in technology management) into the rich body of research regarding IT adoption, use, and diffusion. Finally, we discuss implications and recommend guidelines for research and practice.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2736&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT adoption</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>post-adoptive behavior</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT value</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2737</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>What Happens After ERP Implementation:  Understanding the Impact of Interdependence and Differentiation on Plant-Level Outcomes</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gattiker, Thomas F.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Goodhue, Dale L.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>We present a model of the organizational impacts of enterprise resource planning (ERP) systems once the system has gone live and the “shake-out” phase has occurred.  Organizational information processing theory states that performance is influenced by the level of fit between information processing mechanisms and organizational context.  Two important elements of this context are interdependence and differentiation among subunits of the organization.  Because ERP systems include data and process integration, the theory suggests that ERP will be a relatively better fit when interdependence is high and differentiation is low. Our model focuses at the subunit level of the organization (business function or location, such as a manufacturing plant) and includes intermediate benefits through which ERP’s overall subunit impact occurs (in our case, at the plant level).  ERP customization and the amount of time since ERP implementation are also included in the model.     The resulting causal model is tested using a questionnaire survey of 111 manufacturing plants.   The data support the key assertions in the model.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2737&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Organizational information processing rheory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>enterprise systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ERP</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>data integration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>interdependence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>differentiation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>manufacturing planning and control</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2724</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Effective Use of Knowledge Management Systems:  A Process Model of Content Ratings and Credibility Indicators</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Poston, Robin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Speier, Cheri</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss2/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2724&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge management systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge usage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>decision making</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>content ratings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>and credibility indicators</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2725</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Knowledge Acquisition via Three Learning Processes in Enterprise Information Systems: Learning-by-Investment, Learning-by-Doing, and Learning-from-Others</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ryu, Chungsuk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kim, Yong Jin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chaudhury, Abhijit</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rao, H. Raghav</dc:creator>
<dc:description>An enterprise information portal (EIP) is viewed as a knowledge community.  Activity theory provides a framework to study such a community: members of an EIP conduct specific tasks that are assigned through a division of labor.  Each member of an enterprise information portal EIP) can undergo three distinct types of learning processes: learning-by-investment, learning-by-doing, and learning-from-others.  Through these three types of learning processes, each member achieves specialized knowledge that is related to his or her own task.  Cumulative knowledge resulting from the learning processes is considered in terms of two distinct attributes:  depth and breadth of knowledge.  This paper formulates a mathematical model and defines the goal of an EIP member as maximizing the net benefits of knowledge resulting from individual investment and effort.  Numerical examples are provided to analyze patterns of optimal investment and effort plans as well as the resulting accumulated knowledge.  The results provide useful managerial implications.  In business conditions characterized by high interest rates or high internal rate of returns, it is preferable for members to delay spending their resources for learning.  Intensive investment and efforts to obtain knowledge are preferable when the discount rate of costs is high, when knowledge is durable, when the value of knowledge is high, when the initial level of knowledge is high, when the productivity of the learning process is high, and when sufficient knowledge is transferred from other members.  On the other hand, the size of the EIP has a positive or negative effect depending on the attribute of knowledge and the productivity of learning processes.  Further properties of the optimal decisions and learning processes are analyzed and discussed</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss2/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2725&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>enterprise information portals</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>learning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>activity theory</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2726</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Assessing Value in Organizational Knowledge Creation:   Considerations for Knowledge Workers</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Chen, Andrew N. K.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Edgington, Theresa M.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>To maintain competitive advantage, a firm&#39;s investment decisions related to knowledge creation are likely to be strategic in nature. However, strategic investments usually have an element of risk linked to uncertain and deferred investment benefits. To date, such investment decisions relating to knowledge workers have not been extensively researched. In this paper, we explore the following research question:  How do we strategically assess knowledge creation over time giving consideration to complex decision criteria in order to improve organizational value?  We develop a model based on economic and organization theory for assessing organizational value with regard to knowledge creation investments. Our model prototype provides managers with a learning tool relating to the timing and selection of knowledge creation investments. Our own use of the tool in simulation experiments yielded several insights which suggest that the decisions typically made by managers may dilute knowledge creation investments. Our results demonstrate that the organizational benefit of knowledge creation processes should be well aligned with near-term tasks. Under instances of high knowledge depreciation, however, it is unlikely that individual workers can optimize knowledge creation process decisions without organizational involvement in matching skills to task complexities. The organizational benefits of consistent and frequent knowledge creation process participation increase over time as the match of skills and task complexities improve.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss2/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2726&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge creation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational dynamics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>task characteristics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>economic theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2722</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Special Issue on Information Technology and Knowledge Management</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sambamurthy, V.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Subramani, Mani</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2722&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2827</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>EDITOR’S NOTES Volume 29 Iss. 3</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2827&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2828</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Guest Editorial:  A Valued Institution Builder:  Gordon B. Davis</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ives, Blake</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Olson, Margrethe H.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weber, Ron</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2828&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2826</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments Volume 29 Iss. 2</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss2/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2826&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2716</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Special Issue on information technologies and  knowledge management</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sambamurthy, V.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Subramani, Mani</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss2/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2716&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2727</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Information Technology Relatedness, Knowledge Management Capability, and Performance of Multibusiness Firms</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Tanriverdi, Hüseyin</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Business value of IT is an enduring research question. The elusive link between IT and financial firm performance calls for further research into intermediate organizational variables through which IT may influence firm performance. This study proposes that knowledge management (KM) is a critical organizational capability through which IT influences firm performance. In the context of multibusiness firms, the study examines how the IT resources of a firm should be organized and managed to enhance the firm’s KM capability, and whether and how KM capability influences firm performance. The study develops two hypothesizes: (1) IT relatedness of the firm’s business units enhances cross-unit KM capability; (2) KM capability, in turn, leads to superior firm performance. Data from 250 Fortune1000 firms provide empirical support for these hypotheses. IT relatedness of business units enhances the cross-unit KM capability of the firm. The KM capability creates and exploits cross-unit synergies from the product, customer, and managerial knowledge resources of the firm. These synergies increase the financial performance of the firm. IT relatedness also has significant indirect effects on firm performance through the mediation of KM capability.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss2/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2727&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT relatedness</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge management capability</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>complementarity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>corporate perrformance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>multibusiness firms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>diversification</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>coordination</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>synergy</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2728</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Emergence of Boundary Spanning Competence in Practice:  Implications for Implementation and Use of Information Systems</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Levina, Natalia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vaast, Emmanuelle</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper investigates how an organizational competence in boundary spanning emerges in practice by drawing on the concepts of boundary spanner and boundary object. Using data from two qualitative field studies, we argue that in order for boundary spanning to emerge, a new joint field of practice must be produced. Our data illustrate that agents partially transform their practices in local settings so as to accommodate the interests of their counterparts. While negotiating the new joint field, agents become what we call boundary spanners-in-practice who produce and use objects which then become locally useful and which acquire a common identity–hence, boundary objects-in-use. Moreover, we show how boundary spanners-in-practice use various organizational and professional resources including the influence that comes with being nominated to boundary spanners’ roles to create the new joint field. The conditions necessary for boundary spanners-in-practice to emerge are outlined and discussed, as are important implications for IS implementation and use.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss2/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2728&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Boundary spanning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>boundary objects</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>boundary spanners</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>boundaries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>practice theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Boudrieu</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational learning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>client-consultant relationship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>intranet</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>roles</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2729</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Running in Packs to Develop Knowledge-Intensive Technologies</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Van de Ven, Andrew H.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Advances in information technologies and the growth of a knowledge-based service economy are transforming the basis of technological innovation and corporate competition.  This transformation requires taking a broader, institutional and political view of information technology and knowledge management.  To succeed, firms are advised to focus on building their distinctive competencies, outsource the rest, and become nodes in value chain networks.  This shifts the level of competition from between individual firms to between networks of firms.  In these networks, individual firms or entrepreneurs seldom have the resources, power, or legitimacy to produce change alone.  As a result, “running in packs” is often more successful than “going it alone” to develop and commercialize knowledge-intensive technologies.  Many different actors in public and private sectors make important contributions.  These actors do not play impartial roles; instead, they are active participants who become embroiled in diverse, partisan, and em bedded issues of innovation development.  In this setting, success requires not only technical and rational competence, but also political savvy to understand and mobilize the interests of other players with stakes in an emerging industry.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss2/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2729&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>competence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>infrastructure</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2718</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Why Should I Share?  Examining Social Capital and Knowledge Contribution in Electronic Networks of Practice</dc:title>
<dc:creator>McLure-Wasko, Molly</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Faraj, Samer</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Electronic networks of practice are computer-mediated discussion forums focused on problems of practice that enable individuals to exchange advice and ideas with others based on common interests.  However, why individuals help strangers in these electronic networks is not well understood:  there is no immediate benefit to the contributor, and free-riders are able to acquire the same knowledge as everyone else.  To understand this paradox, we apply theories of collective action to examine how individual motivations and social capital influence knowledge contribution in electronic networks.  This study reports on the activities of one electronic network supporting a professional legal association.  Using archival, network, survey, and content analysis data, we empirically test a model of knowledge contribution.  We find that people contribute their knowledge when they perceive that it enhances their professional reputations, when they have the experience to share, and when they are structurally embedded in the network.  Surprisingly, contributions occur without regard to expectations of reciprocity from others or high levels of commitment to the network.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2718&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Electronic networks of practice</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online communities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social capital</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2719</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Antecedents of Knowledge Transfer from Consultants to Clients in Enterprise System Implementations</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ko, Dong-Gil</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kirsch, Laurie J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>King, William R.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Enterprise resource planning (ERP) systems and other complex information systems represent critical organizational resources.  For such systems, firms typically use consultants to aid in the implementation process.  Client firms expect consultants to transfer their implementation knowledge to their employees so that they can contribute to successful implementations and learn to maintain the systems independent of the consultants.  This study examines the antecedents of knowledge transfer in the context of such an interfirm complex information systems implementation environment.  Drawing from the knowledge transfer, information systems, and communication literatures, an integrated theoretical model is developed that posits that knowledge transfer is influenced by knowledge-related, motivational, and communication-related factors.  Data were collected from consultant-and-client matched-pair samples from 96 ERP implementation projects.  Unlike most prior studies, a behavioral measure of knowledge transfer that incorporates the application of knowledge was used.  The analysis suggests that all three groups of factors influence knowledge transfer, and provides support for 9 of the 13 hypotheses. The analysis also confirms two mediating relationships.  These results (1) adapt prior research, primarily done in non-IS contexts, to the ERP implementation context, (2) enhance prior findings by confirming the significance of an antecedent that has previously shown mixed results, and (3) incorporate new IS-related constructs and measures in developing an integrated model that should be broadly applicable to the interfirm IS implementation context and other IS situations.  Managerial and research implications are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2719&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge transfer</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>enterprise systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ERP</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>consultants</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>structural equation modeling</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>partial least squares</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2824</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>EDITOR’S COMMENTS Volume 29 Iss. 1</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2824&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2717</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Vicious and Virtuous Circles in the Management of Knowledge:  The Case of Infosys Technologies</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Garud, Raghu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kumaraswamy, Arun</dc:creator>
<dc:description>A systems perspective is adopted to explore the challenges that organizations face in harnessing knowledge. A systems perspective draws attention to mutually causal processes that have the potential to generate both vicious and virtuous circles. Based on a longitudinal study at Infosys Technologies, we conclude that knowledge management involves more than just the sponsorship of initiatives at and across different organizational levels. It also involves an active process of steering around and out of vicious circles that will inevitably emerge.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2717&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>increasing returns</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>systems dynamics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>vicious circles</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2825</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Reviewer Acknowledgments Volume 29 Iss. 1</dc:title>
<dc:date>2005-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2825&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2709</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Reach and Grasp</dc:title>
<dc:creator>King, John Leslie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lyytinen, Kalle</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The short history of Information Systems suggests persistent anxiety about the field’s purported lack of academic legitimacy.  A common refrain in the anxiety discourse is that legitimacy can be obtained only by creating a strong theoretic core  for the field.  This essay takes exception with this view, attributing the anxiety to the field’s relative youth, its focus on technology in a technophobic  institutional environment, and academic ethnocentrism within and without the field.  While developing stronger theory might be helpful, it is more important that the IS field pushes back against the hegemony of IS critics outside the field whose arguments masquerade as concerns about academic quality. The anxiety discourse should be replaced by the IS field’s aggressive pursuit of new instructional and research opportunities that cross traditional institutional barriers and the pursuit of  excellence on academic criteria deemed important by the field itself.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2709&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information Systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>legitimacy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>theoretic core</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>discipline</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>disciplinary</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>academic politics</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2710</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Innovating Mindfully with Information Technology</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Swanson, E. Burton</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ramiller, Neil C.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Although organizational innovation with information technology (IT) is often carefully considered, bandwagon phenomena indicate that much innovative behavior may nevertheless be of the “me too” variety.  In this essay, we explore such differences in innovative behavior.  Adopting a perspective that is both institutional and cognitive, we introduce the notion of mindful innovation with IT.  A mindful firm attends to an IT innovation with reasoning grounded in its own organizational facts and specifics.  We contrast this with mindless innovation, where a firm’s actions betray an absence of such attention and grounding.  We develop these concepts by drawing on the recent appearance of the idea of mindfulness in the organizational literature, and adapting it for application to IT innovation.  We then bring mindfulness and mindlessness together in a larger theoretical synthesis in which these apparent opposites are seen to interact in ways that help to shape the overall landscape of opportunity for organizational innovation with IT.  We conclude by suggesting several promising new research directions.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2710&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2711</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>An Empirical Investigation of Net-Enabled Business Value</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Barua, Anitesh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Konana, Prabhudev</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Whinston, Andrew B.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yin, Fang</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Many traditional organizations have undertaken major initiatives to leverage the Internet to transform how they coordinate value activities with customers, suppliers, and other business partners with the objective of improving firm performance. This paper addresses processes through which business value is created through such Internet-enabled value chain activities. Relying on the resource-based view of the firm, we propose a model positing that a firm’s abilities to coordinate and exploit firm resources (processes, information technology, and readiness of customers and suppliers) create online informational capabilities  (a higher order resource) which then leads to improved operational and financial performance. The outcome of a firm’s online informational capabilities is reflected in superior operational performance through customer and supplier-side digitization efforts, which reflect the extent to which transactions and external interactions occur electronically. We also hypothesize that increased customer and supplier-side digitization leads to better financial performance. The model is tested with data from over 1,000 firms in the manufacturing, retail, and wholesale sectors. The analysis suggests that while most firms are lagging in their supplier-side initiatives relative to the customer-side, supplier-side digitization has a strong positive impact on customer-side digitization, which, in turn, leads to better financial performance. Further, both customer and supplier readiness to engage in digital interactions are shown to be as important as a firm’s internal digitization initiatives, implying that a firm’s transformation-related decisions should include its customers’ and suppliers’ resources and incentives.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2711&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Business value of IT</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>net-enabled business transformation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>digitization</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>resource-based view</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online informational capability</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business process alignment</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2712</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Role of Individual Memory and Attention Processes During Electronic Brainstorming</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Potter, Richard E.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Balthazard, Pierre</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Electronic brainstorming (EBS) applications and their methodologies may have achieved the benchmark of enabling interactive users to perform as well as nominal groups.  The current challenge is to view this as a plateau and not an endpoint, and to seek ways of improving EBS performance.  In this study, we apply theory from cognitive psychology and adopt the individual, rather than the group, as the unit of analysis.  We present a model of idea generation cognition based on Hintzman’s MINERVA2 global matching model of memory cognition and additional literature from cognitive psychology on cueing and categorization.  Based on this model, we present a technique called cause cueing, which directs subjects’ attention to the causes of the target problem that they themselves have identified, and hypothesize that this will increase the number of ideas that an individual generates.  Also based on the model—and consistent with current views on production blocking—we hypothesize that receiving input from others during brainstorming will reduce the number of ideas that an individual generates.  Following is an EBS-based study that offers an empirical examination of (1) the effects of cueing attention to natural categories (causes) during idea generation and (2) the effects of cueing attention to ad hoc categories, represented by input from others, during idea generation.  A total of 82 subjects were randomly assigned to one of four conditions in a 2 × 2 factorial design ANOVA experiment.  Results indicate strong support for our model of idea generation as memory cognition.  Cueing participant attention to natural self-generated search categories via the cause cueing technique greatly increased the generation of ideas and high quality ideas, whether or not participants were also cued to attend to ad hoc categories (input from others).  Cueing attention to input from others was detrimental to the generation of ideas and the number of high quality ideas, clearly diminishing the positive effects of cueing to natural categories.  We explain how our theorizing and results are consistent with and extend earlier production blocking orientations in EBS research.  We also examine limitations of current EBS designs and suggest how prevailing methodologies can be modified to better support idea generation cognition.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2712&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Ideation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>brainstorming</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>memory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cognitive load</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>EMS</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>GSS</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2713</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Bridging User Organizations:  Knowledge Brokering and the Work of Information Technology Professionals</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pawlowski, Suzanne D.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robey, Daniel</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This interpretive case study examines knowledge brokering as an aspect of the work of information technology professionals.  The purpose of this exploratory study is to understand knowledge brokering from the perspective of IT professionals as they reflect upon their work practice.  As knowledge brokers, IT professionals see themselves as facilitating the flow of knowledge about both IT and business practices across the boundaries that separate work units within organizations.  A qualitative analysis of interviews conducted with 23 IT professionals and business users in a large manufacturing and distribution company is summarized in a conceptual framework showing the conditions, practices, and consequences of knowledge brokering by IT professionals.  The framework suggests that brokering practices are conditioned by structural conditions, including decentralization and a federated IT management organization, and by technical conditions, specifically shared IT systems that serve as boundary objects.  Brokering practices include gaining permission to cross organizational boundaries, surfacing and challenging assumptions made by IT users, translation and interpretation, and relinquishing ownership of knowledge.  Consequences of brokering are the transfer of both business and IT knowledge across units in the organization.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2713&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Boundary spanning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational communication</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational learning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS skill requirements</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT professionals</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge broker</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>internal knowledge transfer</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2714</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Business Competence of Information Technology Professionals:  Conceptual Development and Influence on IT-Business Partnerships</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Bassellier, Geneviève</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benbasat, Izak</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This research aims at improving our understanding of the concept of the business competence of information technology professionals and at exploring the contribution of this competence to the development of partnerships between IT professionals and their business clients. Business competence focuses on the areas of knowledge that are not specifically IT-related. At a broad level, it comprises the organization-specific knowledge and the interpersonal and management knowledge possessed by IT professionals. Each of these categories is in turn inclusive of more specific areas of knowledge. Organizational overview, organizational unit, organizational responsibility, and IT-business integration form the organization-specific knowledge, while interpersonal communication, leadership, and knowledge networking form the interpersonal and management knowledge. Such competence is hypothesized to be instrumental in increasing the intentions of IT professionals to develop and strengthen the relationship with their clients.   The first step in the study was to develop a scale to measure business competence of IT professionals. The scale was validated and then used to test the model that relates competence to intentions to form IT-business partnerships.  The results support the suggested structure for business competence and indicate that business competence significantly influences the intentions of IT professionals to develop partnerships with their business clients.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2714&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Business competence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business knowledge</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT professionals</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>measurement</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2715</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>User Acceptance of Hedonic Information Systems</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Van der Heijden, Hans</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper studies the differences in user acceptance models for productivity-oriented (or utilitarian) and pleasure-oriented (or hedonic) information systems. Hedonic information systems aim to provide self-fulfilling rather than instrumental value to the user, are strongly connected to home and leisure activities, focus on the fun-aspect of using information systems, and encourage prolonged rather than productive use. The paper reports a cross-sectional survey on the usage intentions for one hedonic information system. Analysis of this sample supports the hypotheses that perceived enjoyment and perceived ease of use are stronger determinants of intentions to use than perceived usefulness. The paper concludes that the hedonic nature of an information system is an important boundary condition to the validity of the technology acceptance model. Specifically, perceived usefulness loses its dominant predictive value in favor of ease of use and enjoyment.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2715&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>User acceptance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology acceptance model</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hedonic information systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>perceived enjoyment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>perceived ease of use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>perceived usefulness</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2822</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Author Index Volume 28</dc:title>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2822&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2701</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Special Issue on Action Research In Informaton Systems: Making IS Research relevant to practice foreword</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Baskerville, Richard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Myers, Michael D.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2004-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss3/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2701&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2702</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Networks of Action:  Sustainable Health Information Systems Across Developing Countries</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Braa, Jørn</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Monteiro, Eric</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sahay, Sundeep</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Our paper is motivated by one simple question: Why do so many action research efforts fail to persist over time?  We approach this question, the problem of sustainability, building on a perspective on action research identifying the pivotal importance of networks.  More precisely, local action research interventions need to be conceptualized and approached as but one element in a larger network of action in order to ensure sustainability.  A vital aspect of our perspective is that local interventions depend heavily on the support of similar action research efforts in other locations.  This is essential for the necessary processes of learning and experience sharing.  We suggest that the scaling (i.e., spreading) of the intervention is a prerequisite, not a luxury, for sustainable action research. Empirically, we base our analysis on an ongoing, large-scale action research project within the health care sector (called HISP) in a number of developing countries. HISP provides a fruitful occasion to investigate key criteria for our approach to action research, namely sustainability, scalability, and capacity to be politically relevant to the participants. We contribute to three discourses:  (1) models of action  research, (2) lessons for health information systems in developing countries, and (3) more generally, IS implementations that are dispersed, large-scale, and have scarce resources.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss3/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2702&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Action research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>networks</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sustainability</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>politics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>health information systems</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2703</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Informating the Clan: Controlling Physicians’ Costs and Outcomes</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kohli, Rajiv</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kettinger, William J.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Past literature recognizes the power of information technology to establish greater transparency and, in turn, the potential for greater control .Theoretical perspectives such as informating and agency theory describe situations whereby legitimized management authority can control goal divergence by implementing information systems to better monitor agents’ behavior and outcomes. But what happens when the principal does not possess legitimacy to impose an agent’s use of information and/or behavioral conformance?  This study investigates this situation.  Through an action research project, a physicians’ profiling system (PPS) was used to monitor and benchmark physicians’ clinical practices and outcomes resulting in changed practice behaviors in closer congruence with management’s goals.  The PPS project represents a successful attempt of a hospital’s management (principal) to &#34;informate the clan&#34; of physicians (agents) to reduce clinical procedural costs and adopt practices benchmarked to produce better outcomes.  This research moves beyond directly controlling informated workers through legitimized managerial authority to a better understanding of how to informate autonomous professionals.  Emerging insights suggest that a clan can be informated if the principal can improve the perceived legitimacy of the information (the message), legitimize the technical messenger (customized user interface), legitimize the human messenger (boundary spanners and influential clan members), and facilitate an environment where clan-based discussion, using the information provided by the principal, is incorporated into the process of concertive control.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss3/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2703&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Action research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>informating</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>clan</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>control and IT implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT-based performance monitoring</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>agency theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>concertive control</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>health care information systems</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2821</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Subject Index Volume 28</dc:title>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2821&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2823</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Reviewers Volume 28</dc:title>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2823&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2704</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Managing Risk in Software Process Improvement:  An Action Research Approach</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Iversen, Jakob H.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mathiassen, Lars</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nielsen, Peter Axel</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Many software organizations engage in software process improvement (SPI) initiatives to increase their capability to develop quality solutions at a competitive level.  Such efforts, however, are complex and very demanding.  A variety of risks makes it difficult to develop and implement new processes.  We studied SPI in its organizational context through collaborative practice research (CPR), a particular form of action research.  The CPR program involved close collaboration between practitioners and researchers over a three-year period to understand and improve SPI initiatives in four Danish software organizations.  The problem of understanding and managing risks in SPI teams emerged in one of the participating organizations and led to this research.  We draw upon insights from the literature on SPI and software risk management as well as practical lessons learned from managing SPI risks in the participating software organizations.  Our research offers two contributions.  First, we contribute to knowledge on SPI by proposing an approach to understand and manage risks in SPI teams.  This risk management approach consists of a framework for understanding risk areas and risk resolution strategies within SPI and a related process for managing SPI risks.  Second, we contribute to knowledge on risk management within the information systems and software engineering disciplines.  We propose an approach to tailor risk management to specific contexts.  This approach consists of a framework for understanding and choosing between different forms of risk management and a process to tailor risk management to specific contexts.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss3/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2704&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Risk management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>software process improvement</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>action research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>collaborative practice research</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2705</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Design Principles for Competence Management Systems: A Synthesis of an Action Research Study</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Lindgren, Rikard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Henfridsson, Ola</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Schultze, Ulrike</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Even though the literature on competence in organizations recognizes the need to align organization level core competence with individual level job competence, it does not consider the role of information technology in managing competence across the macro and micro levels.  To address this shortcoming, we embarked on an action research study that develops and tests design principles for competence management systems.  This research develops an integrative model of competence that not only outlines the interaction between organizational and individual level competence and the role of technology in this process, but also incorporates a typology of competence (competence-in-stock, competence-in-use, and competence-in-the-making).  Six Swedish organizations participated in our research project, which took 30 months and consisted of two action research cycles involving numerous data collection strategies and interventions such as prototypes.  In addition to developing a set of design principles and considering their implications for both research and practice, this article also includes a self-assessment of the study by evaluating it according to the criteria for canonical action research.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss3/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2705&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Canonical action research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>competence management systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>core competence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>design principles</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>HR management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>prototypes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>skill-based approach</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2706</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Small Business Growth and Internal Transparency: The Role of Information Systems</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Street, Christopher T.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Meister, Darren B.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>While many large businesses start out as a small enterprise, remarkably little is known about how an organization actually changes internally during the periods of growth. Small business growth is known to strain internal communication processes, for example, which likely limits growth opportunities. Information systems are often called upon to remedy such deficiencies. Through a participatory action research project, we investigated the ways in which a small business management team developed an IS-enabled solution to address their growth needs. During the progression of the project, a new outcome of organizational effectiveness, internal transparency, was identified and developed. Adopting a punctuated equilibrium perspective, a theoretical process model is proposed that sheds light on a relationship between internal transparency, small business growth and IS.  The paper concludes with observations that internal transparency may well be a concept that offers significant potential for MIS research as well as a discussion about the applicability and credibility of participatory action research for this project.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss3/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2706&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Business growth</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT investment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>small business</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>internal transparency</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>process models</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2707</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Dialogical Action Research at Omega Corporation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Mårtensson, Pär</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lee, Allen S.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In dialogical action research, the scientific researcher does not “speak science” or otherwise attempt to teach scientific theory to the real-world practitioner, but instead attempts to speak the language of the practitioner and accepts him as the expert on his organization and its problems.  Recognizing the difficulty that a practitioner and a scientific researcher can have in communicating across the world of science and the world of practice, dialogical action research offers, as its centerpiece, reflective one-on-one dialogues between the practitioner and the scientific researcher, taking place periodically in a setting removed from the practitioner’s organization.  The dialogue itself serves as the interface between the world of science, marked by theoria and the scientific attitude, and the world of the practitioner, marked by praxis and the natural attitude of everyday life.  The dialogue attempts to address knowledge heterogeneity, which refers to the different forms that knowledge takes in the world of science and the world of practice, and knowledge contextuality, which refers to the dependence of the meaning of knowledge, such as a scientific theory or professional expertise, on its context.  In successive dialogues, the scientific researcher and the practitioner build a mutual understanding, including an understanding of the organization and its problems.  The scientific researcher, based on one or more of the scientific theories in her discipline, formulates and suggests one or more actions for the practitioner to take in order to solve or remedy a problem in his organization.  Dialogical action research recognizes that the practitioner’s experience, expertise, and tacit knowledge, or praxis, largely shapes how he understands the suggested actions and appropriates them as his own.  Upon returning to his organization, he takes one or more of the suggested actions, depending on his reading of the situation at hand.  The reactions or responses of the problem to the actions or stimuli of the practitioner would embody, in the practitioner’s eyes, success or failure in solving or remedying the problem and, in the scientific researcher’s eyes, evidence confirming or disconfirming the theory on which the action was based.  The scientific researcher may then suggest, based on her theories, additional actions, hence initiating another cycle of action and learning.  To illustrate dialogical action research, this paper reconstructs some dialogues between an information systems researcher and a managing director at a European company called Omega Corporation.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss3/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2707&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Action research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>qualitative research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>research methods</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>case studies</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>phenomenology</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2695</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Operationalizing the Essential Role of the Information Technology Artifact in Information Systems Research: Gray Area, Pitfalls, and the Importance of Strategic Ambiguity</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Whinston, Andrew B.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Geng, Xianjun</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In this paper we argue that a large gray area of information systems research exists, whose relevance to the information technology artifact is subject to significant debate even among IS scholars who support the essential role of the IT artifact. As we explain, not explicitly addressing this gray area can have negative, although often inadvertent, effects on the innovative nature of IS research; we explore this danger through three pitfalls. We then propose a stance of strategic ambiguity to deal with the gray area. Strategic ambiguity calls for deliberately withholding judgment on the relevance of research in the gray area and acceptance of gray-area research provided it meets the excellence required by professional journals. We believe that strategic ambiguity benefits innovative IS research without harming the essential role of the IT artifact.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss2/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2695&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IS discipline</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT artifact</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>gray area</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>strategic ambiguity</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2690</identifier>
		<datestamp>2012-10-27T22:06:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Beta Versus VHS and the Acceptance of Electronic Brainstorming Technology</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Dennis, Alan R.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Reinicke, Bryan</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper argues that much of the past research on electronic brainstorming has been somewhat myopic.  Much as Sony focused on the quality of the picture on its Beta format, we as IS researchers have focused on the number of ideas generated as the dominant measure of electronic brainstorming effectiveness.  When VHS killed Beta, Sony discovered that image quality was a secondary consideration for most VCR users.  Despite the compelling research on its performance benefits, electronic brainstorming has not yet displaced–or even joined–verbal brainstorming as a widely used idea generation technique.  This paper presents arguments that users may not be primarily concerned with the number of ideas generated when planning a brainstorming session, but rather may equally desire group well being and member support.  We present theoretical arguments and empirical evidence suggesting that electronic brainstorming is not as effective as verbal brainstorming at providing group well being and member support. We believe that these arguments may also apply to other group and individual research areas and may also call for a reevaluation of the technology acceptance model (TAM).  Finally, we suggest further research that may help electronic brainstorming avoid the fate of the Beta format.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss1/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2690&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Electronic brainstorming</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>group support systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology acceptance model (TAM)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology adoption</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>brainstorming</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>idea generation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>nominal group technique</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

				
			<resumptionToken completeListSize="1372" cursor="300">509567/oai_dc/400//</resumptionToken>
		
		</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>