<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH
	xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/
		http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2017-03-31T01:53:21Z</responseDate>
	<request verb="ListRecords" resumptionToken="509567/oai_dc/1200//" >http://aisel.aisnet.org/do/oai/</request>
	
	<ListRecords>
			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3069</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-11-03T20:08:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Impact of User Satisfaction with Mandated CRM Use on Employee Service Quality</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hsieh, J. J. Po-An</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rai, Arun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Petter, Stacie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhang, Ting</dc:creator>
<dc:description>An increasing number of organizations are now implementing customer relationship management (CRM) systems to support front-line employees’ service tasks. With the belief that CRM can enhance employees’ service quality, management often mandates employees to use the implemented CRM. However, challenges emerge if/when employees are dissatisfied with using the system. To understand the role of front-line employee users’ satisfaction with their mandated use of CRM in determining their service quality, we conducted a field study in one of the largest telecommunications service organizations in China and gathered time-lagged data from self-reported employee surveys, as well as from the firm’s archival data sources. Our results suggest that employees’ overall user satisfaction (UserSat) with their mandated use of CRM has a positive impact on employee service quality (ESQ) above and beyond the expected positive impacts that job dedication (JD) and embodied service knowledge (ESK) have on ESQ. Interestingly, the positive effect of UserSat on ESQ is comparable to the positive effects of JD and ESK, respectively, on ESQ. Importantly, UserSat and ESK have a substitutive effect on ESQ, suggesting that the impact of UserSat on ESQ is stronger/weaker for employees with lower/higher levels of ESK. Finally, ESQ predicts customer satisfaction with customer service employees (CSWCSE); ESQ also fully mediates the impacts of UserSat and ESK, and partially mediates the impact of JD, on CSWCSE. The results of this study emphasize the importance of user satisfaction in determining employees’ task outcomes when use of an information system is mandated.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2012-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol36/iss4/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3069&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>User satisfaction</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mandatory use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>customer relationship management systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>employee service quality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>job dedication</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>embodied service knowledge</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>task performance</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3215</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments:  The MISQ Review System:  Operational Perspectives</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Goes, Paulo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3215&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3214</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Table of Contents, Volume 38, Issue 4</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3214&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3200</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Internet&#39;s Dirty Secret:  Assessing the Impact of Online Intermediaries on HIV Transmission</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Chan, Jason</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ghose, Anindya</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Online platforms offer access to a larger social group than is generally available through offline contacts, making the Internet an emerging venue for seeking casual sex partners. The ease of seeking sex partners through classified ad sites may promote risky behaviors that increase the transmission of STDs. In this paper, using a natural experiment setup, we investigate whether the entry of a major online personals ad site, Craigslist, increases the prevalence of HIV over a 10 year period from 1999 to 2008 across 33 states in the United States. After controlling for extraneous factors, our results suggest that the entry of Craigslist is related to a 15.9 percent increase in HIV cases. Our analysis suggests that the site entry produces an average of 6,130 to 6,455 cases of HIV infection in the United States each year, mapping out to between $62 million and $65.3 million in annual treatment costs. In addition, the analyses reveal that nonmarket-related casual sex is the primary driver of the increase in HIV cases, in contrast to paid transactions solicited on the site (e.g., escort services and prostitution), which has a negative relationship with HIV trends. These findings are essential to understanding the social routes through which HIV transmission takes place and the extent to which site entry can influence HIV trends. Implications for healthcare practitioners and policy makers are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3200&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Classified ad sites</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>HIV</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Internet</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online intermediaries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>transmission route</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3202</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Multihoming Users’ Preferences for Two-Sided Exchange Networks</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Koh, Tat Koon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fichman, Mark</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Online business-to-business (B2B) exchanges are proliferating, giving firms numerous platforms from which to choose. Many firms are also multihoming, using competing platforms concurrently. In this study, we examine how selling and buying activities on B2B exchanges affect multihoming buyers’ preferences for exchanges. We posit that these activities influence buyers’ perceived returns and risks of using the exchanges, and impact buyers’ preferences. Using a unique dataset of 118 buyers’ participation in two B2B exchanges over seven months, we find that buyers prefer exchanges with more selling activities. However, buyers’ preferences and buying levels on the exchanges are non-monotonically related. At low buying levels, an increase in buying by others positively affects buyers’ preferences. This effect may result from observational learning, where individual buyers learn from other buyers’ behaviors. On the other hand, as buying level increases further on the exchange, competition among buyers also increases. Consequently, buyers lower their preferences for the exchange. In addition, we find that the effects of selling and buying activities on buyers’ preferences change over time. Our results highlight the need to correctly model buyers’ homing behavior; failing to do so could bias the picture of competitive dynamics between platforms and lead to suboptimal strategies by exchanges.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3202&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Online platforms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>B2B exchanges</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>multihoming</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>network effects</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>observational learning</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3201</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Ontology-Based Evaluation of Natural Disaster Management Websites:  A Multistakeholder Perspective</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Chou, Chen-Huei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zahedi, Fatemeh &#34;Miriam&#34;</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhao, Huimin</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In recent years, the world has witnessed a number of severe natural disasters, causing heavy losses to families, communities, and even nations. Natural disaster management (NDM) websites play an important role in assisting people through various disaster stages. However, such websites are complex and there is little research on standards and guidelines for their development and evaluation. In this paper, we develop an ontology-based evaluation tool to assess the utility of NDM websites. Two main groups of stakeholders— experts who are in charge of NDM websites and potential users of such websites—contributed to the process. A total of 73 experts validated the ontology developed for NDM web elements through a Delphi study. These experts also provided importance ratings for web elements in the ontology. In a survey of the second major group of stakeholders—potential users—818 participants provided another set of importance ratings for web elements in the ontology. The design theory in this work is based on utility theory. The metrics for the evaluation of websites are relative utility and absolute utility. Using the evaluation tool, we evaluated the NDM websites of the 50 U.S. states from the perspectives of the two groups of stakeholders. The results indicate a lack of readiness in most of these websites.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3201&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Ontology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>utility theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>natural disaster management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Delphi method</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>website evaluation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>web elements</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>analytic hierarchy process</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3203</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>An Analysis of Pricing Models in the Electronic Book Market</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hao, Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fan, Ming</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In this paper, we develop a game theoretic model to study the pricing of e-books and e-readers under two pricing models: wholesale and agency. We analyze pricing strategies for a publisher and a retailer. We identify the complementary relationship between e-books and e-readers as the main reason for the retailer to set a low e-book price in the wholesale model. Comparing the wholesale and the agency models, we find, in a wide range of market conditions, the price for e-book readers is lower in the agency model, leading to a higher e-book market share. However, a higher e-book price in the agency model lowers e-book consumption. Overall social welfare is lower in the agency model than in the wholesale model. While total consumer surplus is slightly higher in the agency model, largely because of a lower e-reader price, business profit is lower. The publisher, surprisingly, is worse off under the agency model.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3203&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Electronic book</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>e-reader</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>pricing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>agency model</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>wholesale model</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3204</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Strategic Behavior in Online Reputation Systems:  Evidence from Revoking on eBay</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ye, Shun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gao, Guodong (Gordon)</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Viswanathan, Siva</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This study examines how sellers respond to changes in the design of reputation systems on eBay. Specifically, we focus on one particular strategic behavior on eBay’s reputation system: sellers’ explicit retaliation against negative feedback provided by buyers to coerce buyers into revoking their negative feedback. We examine how these strategic sellers respond to removal of their ability to retaliate against buyers. We utilize one key policy change of eBay’s reputation system, which provides a natural experimental setting that allows us to infer the causal impact of the reputation system on seller behavior. Our results show that coercing buyers to revoke their negative feedback through retaliation enables low-quality sellers to manipulate their reputations and masquerade as high-quality sellers. We find that these sellers reacted strongly to eBay’s announcement of a proposed ban on revoking. Interestingly, after the power of these strategic sellers is curtailed, we find evidence that they exert more efforts to improve their reputation scores. This study provides valuable insights about the relationship between reputation system and seller behavior, which have important implications for the design of online reputation mechanisms.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3204&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Reputation mechanisms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online ratings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>quality transparency</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online auctions</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3205</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:24Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Information Discovery and the Long Tail of Motion Picture Content</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kumar, Anuj</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Smith, Michael D.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Telang, Rahul</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Recent papers have shown that, in contrast to the long tail theory, movie sales remain concentrated in a small number of hits. These papers have argued that concentrated sales can be explained, in part, by heterogeneity in quality and increasing returns from social effects. Our research analyzes an additional explanation: how incomplete information may skew sales patterns. We use the movie broadcast on pay-cable channels as an exogenous shock to the availability of information, and analyze how this shock changes the resulting sales distribution.
Our data show that the pay-cable broadcast shifts the distribution of DVD sales toward long tail movies, suggesting an information spillover from the broadcast. We develop a learning-based movie discovery model to precisely quantify the two mechanisms of movie discovery: word-of-mouth from previous sales and information spillover from broadcast. We use this model to estimate the lost DVD sales due to incomplete information. Our study contributes to the literature by analyzing how information provided in one channel can change the assortment of the same products demanded in another channel.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3205&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Incomplete information</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>product discovery</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>multichannel distribution</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>movie industry</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cannibalization</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>movie broadcast</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>DVD sales and rental</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>long tail</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sales distribution</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3206</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:25Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Information Technology and Administrative Efficiency in U.S. State Governments:  A Stochastic Frontier Approach</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pang, Min-Seok</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tafti, Ali</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Krishnan, M. S.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper explores value creation from government use of information technologies (IT). While the majority of studies in the information systems (IS) discipline have focused on discovering IT business value in for-profit organizations, the performance effects of IT in the public sector have not been extensively studied in either the IS or the public administration literature. We examine whether IT improves administrative efficiency in U.S. state governments. Utilizing IT budget data in state governments, the census data on state government expenditures, and a variety of information on public services that states provide, we measure technical efficiency with a stochastic frontier analysis and a translog cost function and estimate the effect of IT spending on efficiency. Our analyses provide evidence for a positive relationship between IT spending and cost efficiency and indicate that, on average, a $1 increase in per capita IT budget is associated with $1.13 in efficiency gains. This study contributes to the IS literature by expanding the scope of IT value research to public sector organizations and provides meaningful implications for elected officials and public sector managers.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3206&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT value</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>public sector</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>U.S. state governments</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>stochastic frontier analysis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>translog cost function</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3207</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:26Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Peer Influence in the Diffusion of iPhone 3G over a Large Social Network</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Godinho de Matos, Miguel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ferreira, Pedro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Krackhardt, David</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In this paper, we study the effect of peer influence in the diffusion of the iPhone 3G across a number of communities sampled from a large dataset provided by a major European Mobile carrier in one country. We identify tight communities of users in which peer influence may play a role and use instrumental variables to control for potential correlation between unobserved subscriber heterogeneity and friends’ adoption. We provide evidence that the propensity of a subscriber to adopt increases with the percentage of friends who have already adopted. During a period of 11 months, we estimate that 14 percent of iPhone 3Gs sold by this carrier were due to peer influence. This result is obtained after controlling for social clustering, gender, previous adoption of mobile Internet data plans, ownership of technologically advanced handsets, and heterogeneity in the regions where subscribers move during the day and spend most of their evenings. This result remains qualitatively unchanged when we control for changes over time in the structure of the social network. We provide results from several policy experiments showing that, with this level of effect of peer influence, the carrier would have hardly benefitted from using traditional marketing strategies to seed the iPhone 3G to benefit from viral marketing.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3207&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Peer influence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>homophily</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>diffusion</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>community identification</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>viral marketing</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3208</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:27Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Harnessing the Power of Self-Organization in an Online Community During Organizational Crisis</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Nan, Ning</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lu, Yong</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Organizational crisis management has traditionally favored a centralized plan-and-control approach. This study explores the possibility for an orderly crisis management process to arise unintentionally from decentralized and spontaneous actions in an online community (i.e., self-organization). Based on complex adaptive systems theory, a multilevel model is developed to account for the logical relation between individual-level actions and interactions in an online community and an organizational-level orderly and rational crisis management process, as described by the organizational crisis management literature. We apply this multilevel model to an analysis of 89,596 posts from an online community that was deeply embedded in an earthquake-induced organizational crisis. Results indicate that fluctuation of message content themes in this online community served to energize continuous input from ordinary organization members. These input actualized new possibilities offered by the technology platform for crisis management actions (i.e., actualized IT affordances). Concatenation of immediate impacts of message content themes and actualized IT affordances formed feedback loops that moderated the crisis management activities toward an efficient trajectory. Our findings challenge the traditional assumption that macro-level order requires micro-level order-seeking behaviors. They suggest the viability of self-organization as a new source of organizational order that complements the traditional centralized plan-and-control approach. Theoretical and empirical implications for harnessing the power of ordinary organization members connected by today’s technology platforms are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3208&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Organizational crisis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>self-organization</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>complex adaptive systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information technology</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3209</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:29Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Looking Toward the Future of IT-Business Strategic Alignment through the Past:  A Meta-Analysis</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gerow, Jennifer E.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Grover, Varun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thatcher, Jason Bennett</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Roth, Philip L.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Research examining the relationship between IT–business strategic alignment (hereafter referred to as alignment) and firm performance (hereafter referred to as performance) has produced apparently conflicting findings (i.e., an alignment paradox). To examine the alignment paradox, we conducted a meta-analysis that probed the interrelationships between alignment, performance, and context constructs. We found the alignment dimensions (intellectual, operational, and cross-domain) demonstrate unique relationships with the different performance types (financial performance, productivity, and customer benefit) and with many of the other constructs in alignment’s nomological network. All mean corrected correlations between dimensions of alignment and dependent variables were positive and most of the credibility interval values in these analyses were also positive. Overall, the evidence gathered from the extant literature suggests there is not much of an alignment paradox. This study contributes to the literature by clarifying the relationships between alignment and performance outcomes and offering insight into sources of inconsistencies in alignment research. By doing so, this paper lays a foundation for more consistent treatment of alignment in future IT research.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3209&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Alignment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business–IT strategic alignment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>alignment paradox</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT value</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>productivity paradox</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>meta-analysis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>review</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3210</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Symbolic Action Research in Information Systems:  Introduction to the Special Issue</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Aakhus, Mark</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ågerfalk, Pär J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lyytinen, Kalle</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Te&#39;eni, Dov</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This special issue introduction explores the need to study information systems as symbolic action systems, defines broadly the research domain and related assumptions, notes the origins of this perspective, articulates its key lines of study, and discusses the state of the field in light of published research. The essay also positions the three papers of the special issue in the broader Information Systems (IS) discourse and notes their specific contribution in bridging so far unconnected streams of research and expanding research methods amenable to symbolic action research. This introductory essay furthermore observes some unique challenges in pulling together the special issue that invited the editors to combat against the tendency to approach communicative processes associated with information systems as primarily psychological processes. In closing we note several lines of inquiry that can strengthen future studies of symbolic action including better design theories, more flexible and open use of methods, and attentive use of rich traditions that inform symbolic action research in　IS.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/13</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3210&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Symbolic action</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information system</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>semiotics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>speech act</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>symbol action</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>communication</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>collaboration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>design</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>research methods</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3211</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:31Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Take Their Word for It:  The Symbolic Role of Linguistic Style Matches in User Communities</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ludwig, Stephan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>de Ruyter, Ko</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mahr, Dominik</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wetzels, Martin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bruggen, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>de Ruyck, Tom</dc:creator>
<dc:description>User communities are increasingly becoming an essential element of companies’ business processes. However, reaping the benefits of such social systems does not always prove effective, often because companies fail to stimulate members’ collaboration continuously or neglect their social integration. Following communication accommodation theory, the authors posit that members’ communication style alignment symbolically reflects their community identification and affects subsequent participation behavior. This research uses text mining to extract the linguistic style properties of 74,246 members’ posts across 37 user communities. Two mixed multilevel Poisson regression models show that when members’ linguistic style matches with the conventional community style, it signals their community identification and affects their participation quantity and quality. Drawing on an expanded view of organizational identification, the authors consider dynamics in members’ social identification by examining trends and reversals in linguistic style match developments. Whereas a stronger trend of alignment leads to greater participation quantity and quality, frequent reversals suggest lower participation quantity. At a community level, greater synchronicity in the linguistic style across all community members fosters individual members’ participation behavior.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/14</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3211&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Linguistic style match (LSM)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>user communities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>text mining</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational identification</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>argument development quality</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3212</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Beyond Being There:  The Symbolic Role of Communication and Identification in Perceptions of Proximity to Geographically Dispersed Colleagues</dc:title>
<dc:creator>O&#39;Leary, Michael Boyer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wilson, Jeanne M.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Metiu, Anca</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Using a mixed-methods approach, we develop the concept of perceived proximity, which is created through communication, shared identity, and the symbolic aspects thereof. Building on previous theoretical work, we create and validate measures of perceived proximity. Then, we compare how perceived proximity and objective distance relate to relationship quality for collocated and geographically dispersed work colleagues. Our results show that perceived proximity (i.e., a cognitive and affective sense of relational closeness) and not physical proximity (i.e., geographic closeness measured in miles or kilometers) affects relationship quality in an international survey of more than 600 people and 1,300 dyadic work relationships. We also find that people’s perceptions of proximity mediate the effects of communication and identification on relationship quality. Using qualitative data (2,289 comments from 1,188 respondents coded into 9 themes), we explore the symbolic meaning of perceived proximity. We show how people can form strong bonds despite being separated by large distances and continue to shift the emphasis from information systems as &#34;pipes&#34; or channels to information systems as vehicles for conveying shared meaning and symbolic value. Our findings have important implications for scholars, managers, systems designers, and members of virtual teams, teleworkers, and other geographically dispersed contexts.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/15</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3212&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Proximity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>distance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>relationships</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>symbolic action</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>geographically dispersed work</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>virtual work</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>telework</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>virtual teams</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>dyads</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mixed methods</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3213</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Knowledge Exchange and Symbolic Action in Social Media-Enabled Electronic Networks of Practice:  A Multilevel Perspective on Knowledge Seekers and Contributors</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Beck, Roman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pahlke, Immanuel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Seebach, Christoph</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Organizational knowledge is one of the most important assets of an enterprise. Therefore, many organizations invest in enterprise social media (ESM) to establish electronic networks of practice and to foster knowledge exchange among employees. ESM improves interaction transparency and can be regarded as a sociotechnical system that provides a language for communication and symbolic action as well as a better sense of others’ social identity. Accordingly, the individual characteristics of knowledge seekers and contributors determine why and how interactions occur. However, existing studies tend to focus only on knowledge contributors’ characteristics and to treat knowledge as an object that needs to be transferred. To address this gap, this study conceptualizes and empirically tests a multilevel model of knowledge exchange in electronic networks of practice (ENoP) that includes the characteristics of knowledge seekers and knowledge contributors as well as their dyadic relationship from an activity-centered language/action point of view. A dataset of 15,505 enterprise microblogging messages reveals that knowledge seekers’ characteristics and relational factors drive knowledge exchanges in social media-enabled ENoP. Focusing on organizations with knowledge exchanges supported by information technology, our research extends prior findings by providing the first evidence that the communicative act expressed by question–answer pairs impacts the quality of knowledge exchanged.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/16</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3213&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge exchange</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>enterprise social media</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>language action view</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic networks of practice</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hierarchical linear modeling</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3216</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-03T20:10:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Volume 38:  Subject Index and Acknowledgments</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2014-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss4/17</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3216&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3186</identifier>
		<datestamp>2014-12-30T21:25:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Know Yourself and Know Your Enemy:  An Analysis of Firm Recommendations and Consumer Reviews in a Competitive Environment</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Jabr, Wael</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zheng, Zhiqiang (Eric)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Reviews and product recommendations at online stores enable customers to readily evaluate alternative products prior to purchase. In this context, firms generate recommendations referring customers to a wider variety of products. They also display customer-generated online reviews in order to facilitate evaluation of those recommended products. This study integrates these two IT artifacts to investigate consumer choice vis-à-vis competing products. We use a dataset we collected from Amazon.com consisting of books, sales ranks, recommendations, reviews, and reviewers. We derive the granular impact of reviews, product referrals, and reviewer opinions on product sale dynamics within a competitive market using comprehensive econometric analyses.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss3/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3186&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Online review</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>eWOM</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>competition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>recommendation system</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>instrument variable</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2348</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-01-12T17:36:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Creation of Favorable User Perceptions: Exploring the Role of Intrinsic Motivation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Venkatesh, Viswanath</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1999-12-31T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol23/iss2/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2348&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2608</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-01-12T17:37:59Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>A Longitudinal Investigation of Personal Computers in Homes: Adoption Determinants and Emerging Challenges</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Venkatesh, Viswanath</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brown, Susan A.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>While technology adoption in the workplace has been studied extensively, drivers of adoption in homes have been largely overlooked. This paper presents the results of a nation-wide, two-wave, longitudinal investigation of the factors driving personal computer (PC) adoption in American homes. The findings revealed that the decisions driving adoption and non-adoption were significantly different. Adopters were driven by utilitarian outcomes, hedonic outcomes (i.e., fun), and social outcomes (i.e., status) from adoption. Non-adopters, on the other hand, were influenced primarily by rapid changes in technology and the consequent fear of obsolescence. A second wave of data collection conducted six months after the initial survey indicated an asymmetrical relationship between intent and behavior, with those who did not intend to adopt a PC following more closely with their intent than those who intended to adopt one. We present important implications for research on adoption of technologies in homes and the workplace, and also discuss challenges facing the PC industry.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2001-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol25/iss1/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2608&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2680</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-01-12T17:39:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>User Acceptance of Information Technology:  Toward a Unified View</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Venkatesh, Viswanath</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Morris, Michael G.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Davis, Gordon B.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Davis, Fred D.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Information technology (IT) acceptance research has yielded many competing models, each with different sets of acceptance determinants. In this paper, we (1) review user acceptance literature and discuss eight prominent models, (2) empirically compare the eight models and their extensions, (3) formulate a unified theory that integrates elements across the eight models, and (4) empirically validate the unified model. The eight models reviewed are the theory of reasoned action, the technology acceptance model, a motivational model, the theory of planned behavior, a model combining the technology acceptance model and the theory of planned behavior, a model of PC utilization, innovation diffusion theory, and social cognitive theory. Using data from four organizations over a six-month period with three points of measurement, the eight models explained between 17 percent and 53 percent of the variance in user intentions to use information technology. Next, a unified theory, called the Unified Theory of Acceptance and Use of Technology (UTAUT), was formulated, with four core determinants of intention and usage, and up to four moderators of key relationships. UTAUT was then tested using the original data and found to outperform the eight individual models (69% adjusted-R2). UTAUT was then confirmed with data from two new organizations with similar results (70% adjusted-R2). UTAUT thus provides a useful tool for managers needing to assess the likelihood of success for new technology introductions and helps them understand the drivers of acceptance in order to proactively design interventions (including training, marketing, etc.) targeted at populations of users that may be less inclined to adopt and use new systems. The paper also makes several recommendations for future research including developing a deeper understanding of the dynamic influences studied here, refining measurement of the core constructs used in UTAUT, and understanding the organizational outcomes associated with new technology use.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2003-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol27/iss3/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2680&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2756</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-01-12T17:43:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Web and Wireless Site Usability:  Understanding Differences and Modeling Use</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Venkatesh, Viswanath</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ramesh, V.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Recent research has presented a conceptualization, metric, and instrument based on Microsoft Usability Guidelines (MUG; see Agarwal and Venkatesh 2002). In this paper, we use MUG to further our understanding of Web and wireless site use. We conducted two empirical studies among over 1,000 participants. In study 1, conducted in both the United States and Finland, we establish the generalizability of the MUG conceptualization, metric, and associated instrument from the United States to Finland. In study 2, which involved longitudinal data collection in Finland, we delved into an examination of differences in factors important in determining Web versus wireless site usability. Also, in study 2, based on a follow-up survey about site use conducted 3 months after the initial survey, we found support for a model of site use that employs the MUG categories and subcategories as predictors. The MUG-based model outperformed the widely employed technology acceptance model both in terms of richness and variance explained (about 70 percent compared to 50 percent).</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol30/iss1/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2756&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Microsoft Usability Guidelines</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology acceptance model</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2731</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-01-12T17:44:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>A Model of Adoption of Technology in the Household:  A Baseline Model Test and Extension Incorporating Household Life Cycle</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Brown, Susan A.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Venkatesh, Viswanath</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Individual adoption of technology has been studied extensively in the workplace. Far less attention has been paid to adoption of technology in the household. In this paper, we performed the first quantitative test of the recently developed model of adoption of technology in the household (MATH). Further, we proposed and tested a theoretical extension of MATH by arguing that key demographic characteristics that vary across different life cycle stages would play moderating roles. Survey responses were collected from 746 U.S. households that had not yet adopted a PC. The results showed that the integrated model, including MATH constructs and life cycle characteristics, explained 74 percent of the variance in intention to adopt a PC for home use, a significant increase over baseline MATH that explained 50 percent of the variance. Finally, we compared the importance of various factors across household life cycle stages and gained a more refined understanding of the moderating role of household life cycle stage.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss3/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2731&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>option</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology adoption</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>household</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>personal computers</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2808</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-02T21:11:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments Volume 27 Iss. 2</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Weber, Ron</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2003-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol27/iss2/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2808&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2819</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-02T21:11:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>EDITOR’S COMMENTS Volume 28 Iss. 3</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Weber, Ron</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2004-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss3/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2819&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2820</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-02T21:11:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments Volume 28 Iss. 4</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Weber, Ron</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2004-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss4/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2820&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2550</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-02T21:11:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Representing Part–Whole Relations in Conceptual Modeling:  An Empirical Evaluation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Shanks, Graeme</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tansley, Elizabeth</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nuredini, Jasmina</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tobin, Daniel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weber, Ron</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The part-of construct is a fundamental element of many conceptual modeling grammars that is used to associate one thing (a component) with another thing (a composite).  Substantive theoretical issues surrounding the part-of construct remain to be resolved, however.  For instance, contrary to widespread claims, some researchers now argue the relationship between components and composites is not always transitive.  Moreover, how the part-of construct should be represented in a conceptual schema diagram remains a contentious issue.  Some analysts argue composites should be represented as a relationship or association.  Others argue they should be represented as an entity.  In this paper we use an ontological theory to support our arguments that composites should be represented as entities and not relationships or associations.  We also describe an experiment that we undertook to test whether representing composites as relationships or entities enables users to understand a domain better.  Our results support our arguments that using entities to represent composites enables users to better understand a domain.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2008-10-27T22:06:23Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol32/iss3/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2550&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Conceptual modeling</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>development</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ontology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>part-of relations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>aggregation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>composition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>meronymic relations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mereology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mereotopology</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2813</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-02T21:11:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments Volume 27 Iss.4</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Weber, Ron</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2009-03-31T17:22:33Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol27/iss4/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2813&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2810</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-02T21:11:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>EDITOR’S COMMENTS</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Weber, Ron</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2004-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss1/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2810&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2817</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-02T21:11:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments Volume 28 Iss. 2</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Weber, Ron</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2004-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol28/iss2/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2817&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3134</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-02T22:14:35Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Control Balancing in Information Systems Development Offshoring Projects</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gregory, Robert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Beck, Roman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Keil, Mark</dc:creator>
<dc:description>While much is known about selecting different types of control that can be exercised in information systems development projects, the control dynamics associated with ISD offshoring projects represent an important gap in our understanding.  In this paper, we develop a substantive grounded theory of control balancing that addresses this theoretical gap.  Based on a longitudinal case study of an ISD offshoring project in the financial services industry, we introduce a three-dimensional control configuration category that emerged from our data, suggesting that control type is only one dimension on which control configuration decisions need to be made. The other two dimensions that we identified are control degree (tight versus relaxed) and control style (unilateral versus bilateral).  Furthermore, we illustrate that control execution during the life cycle of an ISD offshoring project is highly intertwined with the development of client–vendor shared understanding and that each influences the other.  Based on these findings, we develop an integrative process model that explains how offshoring project managers make adjustments to the control configuration periodically to allow the ISD offshoring project and relationship to progress, yielding the iterative use of different three-dimensional control configurations that we conceptualize in the paper.  Our process model of control balancing may trigger new ways of looking at control phenomena in temporary interfirm organizations such as client–vendor ISD offshoring projects.  Implications for research on organizational control and ISD offshoring are discussed.  In addition, guidelines for ISD offshoring practitioners are presented.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2013-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol37/iss4/12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3134&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Control balancing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>control dynamics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational control</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information systems development</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>offshoring projects</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>outsourcing relationships</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>longitudinal case study</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>grounded theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>process model</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>project management</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2527</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-02-03T20:08:30Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Relative Advantage of Electronic Channels:  A Multidimensional View</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Choudhury, Vivek</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karahanna, Elena</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The Internet has the potential to fundamentally change the structure of marketing channels, but only if consumers choose to adopt electronic channels.  Thus, this paper aims to develop a more nuanced understanding of consumer channel choices.  Specifically, it contends that it is important to examine consumers’ intent to adopt electronic channels, not as a monolithic decision, but as a choice they make at each of four stages in the purchase process:  requirements determination, vendor selection, purchase, and after-sales service.
Innovation diffusion theory suggests that consumers make adoption decisions based on their perceptions of the relative advantage of the innovation.  The relative advantage of electronic channels is conceptualized as a multidimensional construct involving a cumulative assessment of the perceived relative merits of channels on three dimensions:  convenience, trust, and efficacy of information acquisition.  Combining the multidimensional nature of relative advantage with the multistage purchase process, the central assertion, and intended contribution, of this paper is to show that the relative advantage of electronic channels, and the influence of each dimension of relative advantage on the adoption of electronic channels, will vary across the different stages of the purchase process.
Survey data were collected from faculty and staff at a large university about their intention to use the web for auto insurance transactions.  The results provide support for the multidimensional nature of relative advantage, although the emergent factors do not align neatly with the hypothesized dimensions (convenience, trust, and efficacy of information acquisition) or stages.  Results of the study support three conclusions.  First, the dimensions along which consumers assess relative advantage blend hypothesized dimensions such as trust and convenience with stages of the purchase process.  Second, consumers consider the relative advantage of channels at two distinct stages of the purchase process:  gathering information and executing the transaction.  Third, different dimensions of relative advantage are critical in predicting consumer channel choice at each stage.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2008-10-10T19:26:37Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol32/iss1/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2527&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Electronic channels</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>relative advantage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>stages in purchasing process</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>B2C e-commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>trust</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>efficacy of information acquisition</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3217</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Table of Contents, Volume 39, Issue 1</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3217&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3218</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments:  Sandy Slaughter:  Outstanding Scholar, Incredible Human Being</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Goes, Paulo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3218&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Sandy Slaughter</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3219</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Motivating Employees to Explore Collaboration Technology in Team Contexts</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Maruping, Likoebe M.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Magni, Massimo</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Firms are increasing their investments in collaboration technologies in order to leverage the intellectual resources embedded in their employees. Research on post-adoption use of technology suggests that the true gains from such investments are realized when users explore various system features and attempt to incorporate them into their work practices. However, the literature has been silent about how to promote such behavior when individuals are embedded in team settings, where members’ actions are interdependent. This research develops a multilevel model that theorizes the cross-level influence of team empowerment on individual exploration of collaboration technology. Further, it identifies two cognitions—intention to continue exploring and expectation to continue exploring—that are oriented toward exploring ways to incorporate implemented technology into daily work routines over time. A 12-month field study of 212 employees in 48 organizational work teams was conducted to test the multilevel research model. The results provide support for the hypotheses, with team empowerment having a positive cross-level influence on intention to continue exploring and expectation to continue exploring and these, in turn, mediating the cross-level influence of team empowerment on individual exploration of collaboration technology.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3219&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Collaboration technology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT exploration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>extended use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>multilevel theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cross-level mediation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>teams</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>empowerment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>post-implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>post-adoption use</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3220</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>How Does the Internet Affect the Financial Market?  An Equilibrium Model of Internet-Facilitated Feedback Trading</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Zhang, Michael (Xiaoquan)</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhang, Lihong</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The ease of Internet stock trading has lured relatively inexperienced investors into the financial markets. This paper is a study of the consequences of the influx of these uninformed traders with a dynamic equilibrium framework. The results show that these strategic, uninformed online traders who adopt feedback strategies cannot outperform those who do not follow feedback strategies and that feedback trading cannot affect market equilibrium. The results also show that an informed trader’s equilibrium strategy and expected profit remain unchanged with or without feedback trading. The presence of feedback trading in the market does not affect the speed at which information gets incorporated into prices. If uninformed traders aggregately adopt a more aggressive feedback trading strategy, they bear a higher risk. It is therefore important to manage and contain these uninformed traders’ risks. The implications for regulating and designing such Internet trading systems are also discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3220&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Financial information</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>financial market</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>feedback strategy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>market stability</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online trading</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3221</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>How Do Enterprise Resource Planning Systems Affect Firm Risk?  Post-Implementation Impact</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Tian, Feng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xu, Sean Xin</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Managing firm risk, or firm performance volatility, is a key task for contemporary firms. Although information technology (IT) has been generally viewed as an effective information processing tool that enables firms to better cope with uncertainty, thus holding the potential to mitigate firm performance volatility, evidence to support this view is lacking in the literature. We theorize that enterprise resource planning (ERP) systems, a major type of enterprise IT applications, can help reduce firm risk and, in particular, we argue that, to uncover the risk reduction effect of ERP systems, a research focus on the post-implementation stage is needed. Based on a sample of 2,127 firm-year observations, we found that ERP systems in the post-implementation stage were associated with reduced firm risk, and that the risk reduction effect was stronger for ERP systems with a greater scope of functional and operational modules, especially functional modules. We further found that, on average, the risk reduction effect of ERP systems became greater when firms’ operating environments feature higher uncertainty, while the risk reduction associated with fully deploying ERP system modules seem to level off as environmental uncertainty increases. These findings extend our understanding of the business value of ERP systems by shedding light on the risk reduction benefit of ERP systems.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3221&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>ERP systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>firm risk</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>performance volatility</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>post-implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>environmental uncertainty</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ERP system scope</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business value</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3222</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Investing in Information Systems:  On the Behavioral and Institutional Search Mechanisms Underpinning Hospitals&#39; IS Investment Decisions</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Salge, Torsten-Oliver</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kohli, Rajiv</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Barrett, Michael</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This study integrates tenets of the behavioral theory of the firm and neo-institutional theory to identify four recurring search mechanisms that are expected to influence hospital managers’ information systems investment decisions. To account for the critical role of regulation in healthcare, senior managers’ reliance on each of these four search mechanisms is hypothesized to be contingent upon their hospital’s regulative legitimacy. Analyses of panel data from all 153 public nonspecialist hospital organizations in England reveal that hospital managers invest in IS not only to find solutions to performance shortfalls (problemistic search), but also to achieve continuity and predictability in resource allocation (institutionalized search) and signal conformity with external norms and expectations (mimetic search). We find that the desire to make adequate use of uncommitted financial resources (slack search) is salient only among hospitals with low levels of regulative legitimacy. These new insights into the motives that trigger—and constrain—senior managers’ IS investment decisions will help IS managers to strengthen their case for IS investment and guide policy makers in how best to allocate resources to IS in healthcare and possibly beyond.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3222&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Decision making</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS investment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business value of IT</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>behavioral theory of the firm</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3224</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>An Enhanced Fear Appeal Rhetorical Framework:  Leveraging Threats to the Human Asset Through Sanctioning Rhetoric</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Johnston, Allen C</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Warkentin, Merrill</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Siponen, Mikko</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Fear appeals, which are used widely in information security campaigns, have become common tools in motivating individual compliance with information security policies and procedures. However, empirical assessments of the effectiveness of fear appeals have yielded mixed results, leading IS security scholars and practitioners to question the validity of the conventional fear appeal framework and the manner in which fear appeal behavioral modeling theories, such as protection motivation theory (PMT), have been applied to the study of information security phenomena. We contend that the conventional fear appeal rhetorical framework is inadequate when used in the context of information security threat warnings and that its primary behavioral modeling theory, PMT, has been misspecified in the extant information security research. Based on these arguments, we propose an enhanced fear appeal rhetorical framework that leverages sanctioning rhetoric as a secondary vector of threats to the human asset, thereby adding the dimension of personal relevance, which is critically absent from previous fear appeal frameworks and PMT-grounded security studies. Following a hypothetical scenario research approach involving the employees of a Finnish city government, we validate the efficacy of the enhanced fear appeal framework and determine that informal sanction rhetoric effectively enhances conventional fear appeals, thus providing a significant positive influence on compliance intentions.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3224&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Fear appeals</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>protection motivation theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>deterrence theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information security</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>threats</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>responses</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sanctions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>rhetoric</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3225</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Service Innovation in the Digital Age:  Key Contribution and Future Directions</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Barrett, Michael</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Davidson, Elizabeth</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Prabhu, Jaideep</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vargo, Stephen L.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3225&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3226</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Service Innovation:  A Service-Dominant Logic Perspective</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Lusch, Robert F.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nambisan, Satish</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In this article, we offer a broadened view of service innovation—one grounded in service-dominant logic—that transcends the tangible–intangible and producer–consumer divides that have plagued extant research in this area. Such a broadened conceptualization of service innovation emphasizes (1)　innovation as a collaborative process occurring in an actor-to-actor (A2A) network, (2)　service as the application of specialized competences for the benefit of another actor or the self and as the basis of all exchange, (3)　the generativity unleashed by increasing resource liquefaction and resource density, and (4)　resource integration as the fundamental way to innovate. Building on these core themes, we offer a tripartite framework of service innovation: (1)　service ecosystems, as emergent A2A structures actors create and recreate through their effectual actions and which offer an organizing logic for the actors to exchange service and cocreate value; (2)　service platforms, which enhance the efficiency and effectiveness of service exchange by liquefying resources and increasing resource density (facilitating easy access to appropriate resource bundles) and thereby serve as the venue for innovation; and (3)　value cocreation, which views value as cocreated by the service offer(er) and the service beneficiary (e.g., customer) through resource integration and indicate the need for mechanisms to support the underlying roles and processes. In discussing these components, we consider the role of information technology—both as an operand resource and as an operant resource—and then examine the implications for research and practice in digitally enabled service innovation.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3226&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Service innovation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>S-D logic</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>platforms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ecosystems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>value cocreation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>collaboration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>resource integration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>institutions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>architecture</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3227</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Value of Self-Service:  Long-Term Effects of Technology-Based Self-Service Usage on Customer Retention</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Scherer, Anne</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wünderlich, Nancy V.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>von Wangenheim, Florian</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Advancements in information technology have changed the way customers experience a service encounter and their relationship with service providers. Especially technology-based self-service channels have found their way into the 21st century service economy. While research embraces these channels for their cost-efficiency, it has not examined whether a shift from personal to self-service affects customer–firm relationships. Drawing from the service-dominant logic and its central concept of value-in-context, we discuss customers’ value creation in self-service and personal service channels and examine the long-term impact of these channels on customer retention. Using longitudinal customer data, we investigate how the ratio of self-service versus personal service use influences customer defection over time. Our findings suggest that the ratio of self-service to personal service used affects customer defection in a U-shaped manner, with intermediate levels of both self-service and personal service use being associated with the lowest likelihood of defection. We also find that this effect mitigates over time. We conclude that firms should not shift customers toward self-service channels completely, especially not at the beginning of a relationship. Our study underlines the importance of understanding when and how self-service technologies create valuable customer experiences and stresses the notion of actively managing customers’ cocreation of value.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3227&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Self-service</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>e-service</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>value-in-context</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>customer retention</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>customer defection</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>longitudinal</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3228</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>The Algorithm and the Crowd:  Considering the Materiality of Service Innovation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Orlikowski, Wanda</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Scott, Susan V.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This special issue acknowledges important innovations in the world of service and within this domain we are particularly interested in exploring the rise and influence of web-based crowd-sourcing and algorithmic rating and ranking mechanisms. We suggest that a useful way to make sense of these digital service innovations and their novel implications is to recognize that they are materialized in practice. We thus need effective conceptual and analytical tools that allow us to take materiality seriously in our studies of service innovation. To this end, we propose some theoretical ideas relating to a sociomaterial perspective, and then highlight empirically how this perspective helps us analyze the specific service materializations enacted through the algorithmic configuring of crowd-sourced data, and how these make a difference in practice to the outcomes produced.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3228&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Algorithms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>crowds</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>innovation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>materiality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>performativity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>practice</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sociomateriality</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3230</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-02T22:25:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Bridging the Service Divide Through Digitally Enabled Service Innovations:  Evidence from Indian Healthcare Service Providers</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Srivastava, Shirish C.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shainesh, G.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The digital divide is usually conceptualized through goods-dominant logic, where bridging the divide entails providing digital goods to disadvantaged segments of the population. This is expected to enhance their digital capabilities and thus to have a positive influence on the digital outcomes (or services) experienced. In contrast, this study is anchored in an alternative service-dominant logic and posits that viewing the divide from a service perspective might be better suited to the context of developing countries, where there is a huge divide across societal segments in accessing basic services such as healthcare and education. This research views the prevailing differences in the level of services consumed by different population segments (service divide) as the key issue to be addressed by innovative digital tools in developing countries. The study posits that information and communication technologies (ICTs) can be leveraged to bridge the service divide to enhance the capabilities of service-disadvantaged segments of society. But such service delivery requires an innovative assembly of ICT as well as non-ICT resources. Building on concepts from service-dominant logic and service science, this paper aims to understand how such service innovation efforts can be orchestrated. Specifically, adopting a process view, two Indian enterprises that have developed sustainable telemedicine healthcare service delivery models for the rural population in India are examined. The study traces the configurations of three interactional resources—knowledge, technology, and institutions—through which value-creating user-centric objectives of increasing geographical access and reducing cost are achieved. The theoretical contributions are largely associated with unearthing and understanding how the three interactional resources were orchestrated for service-centric value creation in different combinative patterns as resource exploitation, resource combination, and value reinforcement. The analysis also reveals the three distinct stages of service innovation evolution (idea and launch, infancy and early growth, and late growth and expansion), with a distinct shift in the dominant resource for each stage. Through an inductive process, the study also identifies four key enablers for successfully implementing these ICT-enabled service innovations: obsessive customer empathy, belief in the transformational power of ICT, continuous recursive learning, and efficient network orchestration.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/14</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3230&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Service innovation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>developing countries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>service divide</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>healthcare</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>process view</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>service science</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>service systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social entrepreneurship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>society</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>digital divide</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>India</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>institutions</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3172</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-03-11T17:00:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Data Collection in the Digital Age:  Innovative Alternatives to Student Samples</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Steelman, Zachary R.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hammer, Bryan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Limayem, Moez</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Online crowdsourcing markets (OCM) are becoming more popular as a source for data collection. In this paper, we examine the consistency of survey results across student samples, consumer panels, and online crowdsourcing markets (specifically Amazon’s Mechanical Turk) both within the United States and outside. We conduct two studies examining the technology acceptance model (TAM) and the expectation– disconfirmation theory (EDT) to explore potential differences in demographics, psychometrics, structural model estimates, and measurement invariances. Our findings indicate that (1)　U.S.-based OCM samples provide demographics much more similar to our student and consumer panel samples than the non-U.S.-based OCM samples; (2)　both U.S. and non-U.S. OCM samples provide initial psychometric properties (reliability, convergent, and divergent validity) that are similar to those of both student and consumer panels; (3)　non-U.S. OCM samples generally provide differences in scale means compared to those of our students, consumer panels, and U.S. OCM samples; and (4)　one of the non-U.S. OCM samples refuted the highly replicated and validated TAM model in the relationship of perceived usefulness to behavioral intentions. Although our post hoc analyses isolated some cultural and demographic effects with regard to the non-U.S. samples in Study 1, they did not address the model differences found in Study 2. Specifically, the inclusion of non-U.S. OCM respondents led to statistically significant differences in parameter estimates, and hence to different statistical conclusions. Due to these unexplained differences that exist within the non-U.S. OCM samples, we caution that the inclusion of non-U.S. OCM participants may lead to different conclusions than studies with only U.S. OCM participants. We are unable to conclude whether this is due to of cultural differences, differences in the demographic profiles of non-U.S. OCM participants, or some unexplored factors within the models. Therefore, until further research is conducted to explore these differences in detail, we urge researchers utilizing OCMs with the intention to generalize to U.S. populations focus on U.S.-based participants and exercise caution in using non-U.S. participants. We further recommend that researchers should clearly describe their OCM usage and design (e.g., demographics, participant filters, etc.) procedures. Overall, we find that U.S. OCM samples produced models that lead to similar statistical conclusions as both U.S. students and U.S. consumer panels at a considerably reduced cost.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol38/iss2/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3172&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Data collection</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>crowdsourcing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sampling</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>crowdsourcing market</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2254</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-03T16:40:18Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Computer Self Efficacy: Development of a Measure and Initial Test</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Compeau, Deborah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Higgins, Christopher</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1995-12-31T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol19/iss2/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2254&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2344</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-03T16:40:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Social Cognitive Theory and Individual Reactions to Computing Technology: A Longitudinal Study</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Compeau, Deborah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Higgins, Christopher</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huff, Sid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1999-12-31T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol23/iss2/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2344&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3229</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:21:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Distributed Tuning of Boundary Resources:  The Case of Apple&#39;s iOS Service System</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eaton, Ben</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elaluf-Calderwood, Silvia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sorensen, Carsten</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yoo, Youngjin</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The digital age has seen the rise of service systems involving highly distributed, heterogeneous, and resource-integrating actors whose relationships are governed by shared institutional logics, standards, and digital technology. The cocreation of service within these service systems takes place in the context of a paradoxical tension between the logic of generative and democratic innovations and the logic of infrastructural control. Boundary resources play a critical role in managing the tension as a firm that owns the infrastructure can secure its control over the service system while independent firms can participate in the service system. In this study, we explore the evolution of boundary resources. Drawing on Pickering’s (1993) and Barrett et al.’s (2012) conceptualizations of tuning, the paper seeks to forward our understanding of how heterogeneous actors engage in the tuning of boundary resources within Apple’s iOS service system. We conduct an embedded case study of Apple’s iOS service system with an in-depth analysis of 4,664 blog articles concerned with 30 boundary resources covering 6 distinct themes. Our analysis reveals that boundary resources of service systems enabled by digital technology are shaped and reshaped through distributed tuning, which involves cascading actions of accommodations and rejections of a network of heterogeneous actors and artifacts. Our study also shows the dualistic role of power in the distributed tuning process.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss1/13</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3229&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Service system innovation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mobile platform</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ecosystem</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>digital infrastructure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>boundary resource dynamics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>tuning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sociomateriality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>iOS</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3232</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:01Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Table of Contents</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3232&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3231</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Guest Editorial:  Research Framework for AIS Grand Vision of the Bright ICT Initiative</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Lee, Jae Kyu</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The Internet has become a minefield of crime, fakes, and terror perpetuated by anonymous users on a global scale. The security burden of protecting organizations is becoming increasingly difficult and costly, and this burden cannot be lessened under the current Internet protocol. In order to fundamentally solve these side effects, the Council of the Association for Information Systems (AIS) has adopted a grand vision of an ICT-Enabled Bright Society (in short, the Bright ICT Initiative). With the goal of preventing undesirable activities on the Internet, diverse issues can be investigated using a bottom-up perspective. Scholars are beginning to examine the concept and various approaches with the support of the AIS conferences and the information system journals. However, a unique approach and fundamental solution must be identified in order to drastically eliminate the negative side effects of these adverse online activities. In order to achieve this, four principles are proposed that will provide the foundation of the framework for a new and safer Internet platform, the Bright Internet, while protecting users’ privacy at an appropriate level. The proposed principles are origin responsibility, deliverer responsibility, rule-based digital search warrants, and traceable anonymity. This endeavor requires the investigation of technologies, policies, and international agreements on which new business models can be created.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3231&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Bright ICT</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bright Internet</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>AIS initiative</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3233</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:03Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>New State of Play in Information Systems Research:  The Push to the Edges</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Grover, Varun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lyytinen, Kalle</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The dominant way of producing knowledge in information systems (IS) seeks to domesticate high-level reference theory in the form of mid-level abstractions involving generic and atheoretical information technology (IT) components. Enacting such epistemic scripts squeezes IS theory to the middle range, where abstract reference theory concepts are directly instantiated or slightly modified to the IS context, whereas IT remains exogenous to theory by being treated as an independent variable, mediator, or moderator. In this design, IT is often operationalized using proxies that detect the presence of IT or its variation in use or cost. Our analysis of 143 articles published in MIS Quarterly and Information Systems Research over the past 15 years demonstrates that over 70 percent of published theory conforms to this mode of producing IS knowledge. This state of play has resulted in two negative consequences: the field (1)　agonizes over the dearth of original and bold theorizing over IT and (2)　satisfices when integrating theory with empirics by creating incommensurate mid-range models that are difficult to consolidate. We propose that one way to overcome these challenges is to critically examine and debate the negative impacts of the field’s dominant epistemic scripts and relax them by permitting IS scholarship that more fluidly accommodates alternative forms of knowledge production. This will push IS inquiry to the &#34;edges&#34; and emphasize, on the one hand, inductive, rich inquiries using innovative and extensive data sets and, on the other hand, novel, genuine, high-level theorizing around germane conceptual relationships between IT, information and its (semiotic) representations, and social behaviors. We offer several exemplars of such inquiries and their results. To promote this push, we invite alternative institutionalized forms of publishing and reviewing. We conclude by inviting individual scholars to be more open to practices that permit richer theorizing. These recommendations will broaden the field’s knowledge ecology and permit the creation of good IS knowledge over just getting &#34;hits.&#34; We surmise that, if such changes are carried out, the field can look confidently toward its future as one of the epicenters of organizational inquiry that deal with the central forces shaping human enterprise in the 21st century.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3233&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information systems discipline</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>research inquiry</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>epistemic scripts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT artifact</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>middle-range theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>theory borrowing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>institutional analysis</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3234</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Consistent Partial Least Squares Path Modeling</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Dijkstra, Theo K.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Henseler, Jörg</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper resumes the discussion in information systems research on the use of partial least squares (PLS) path modeling and shows that the inconsistency of PLS path coefficient estimates in the case of reflective measurement can have adverse consequences for hypothesis testing. To remedy this, the study introduces a vital extension of PLS: consistent PLS (PLSc). PLSc provides a correction for estimates when PLS is applied to reflective constructs: The path coefficients, inter-construct correlations, and indicator loadings become consistent. The outcome of a Monte Carlo simulation reveals that the bias of PLSc parameter estimates is comparable to that of covariance-based structural equation modeling. Moreover, the outcome shows that PLSc has advantages when using non-normally distributed data. We discuss the implications for IS research and provide guidelines for choosing among structural equation modeling techniques.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3234&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>PLS</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>consistent partial least squares</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>SEM</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>variance-based structural equation modeling</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Monte Carlo simulation</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3236</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:07Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Increasing Accountability Through User-Interface Design Artifacts:  A New Approach to Addressing the Problem of Access-Policy Violations</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Vance, Anthony Osborn</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lowry, Paul Benjamin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eggett, Dennis</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Access-policy violations are a growing problem with substantial costs for organizations. Although training programs and sanctions have been suggested as a means of reducing these violations, evidence shows the problem persists. It is thus imperative to identify additional ways to reduce access-policy violations, especially for systems providing broad access to data. We use accountability theory to develop four user-interface (UI) design artifacts that raise users’ accountability perceptions within systems and in turn decrease access-policy violations. To test our model, we uniquely applied the scenario-based factorial survey method to various graphical manipulations of a records system containing sensitive information at a large organization with over 300 end users who use the system daily. We show that the UI design artifacts corresponding to four submanipulations of accountability can raise accountability and reduce access policy violation intentions. Our findings have several theoretical and practical implications for increasing accountability using UI design. Moreover, we are the first to extend the scenario-based factorial survey method to test design artifacts. This method provides the ability to use more design manipulations and to test with fewer users than is required in traditional experimentation and research on human–computer interaction. We also provide bootstrapping tests of mediation and moderation and demonstrate how to analyze fixed and random effects within the factorial survey method optimally.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3236&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Accountability theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>identifiability</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>expectation of evaluation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>awareness of monitoring</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social presence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>factorial survey method</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>user-interface design</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information security policy violations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>unauthorized access</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mediation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>moderation</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3237</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:08Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Coping with Information Technology:  Mixed Emotions, Vacillation, and Nonconforming Use Patterns</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Stein, Mari-Klara</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Newell, Sue</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wagner, Erica L</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Galliers, Robert D</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Achieving the promised business benefits of an IT system is intimately tied to the continued incorporation of the system into the work practices it is intended to support. While much is known about different social, cognitive, and technical factors that influence initial adoption and use, less is known about the role of emotional factors in users’ behaviors. Through an in-depth field study conducted in two North American universities, we examine the role of emotions in how specific IT use patterns emerge. We find that there are five different characteristics of an IT stimulus event (cues) that, when interacting in a reinforcing manner, elicit a single class of emotions (uniform affective responses) and, when interacting in an oppositional manner, elicit mixed emotions (ambivalent affective responses). While users respond to uniform emotions with clear adaptation strategies, they deal with ambivalent emotions by combining different adaptation behaviors, a vacillating strategy between emphasizing positive and negative aspects of the stimulus. Surprisingly, these ambivalent emotions and vacillating strategies can lead to active and positive user engagement, exhibited in task and tool adaptation behaviors and improvisational use patterns that, despite their nonconformity to terms of use, can have positive organizational implications.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3237&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Emotions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT use patterns</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>adaptation behaviors</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ambivalence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>qualitative research</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3238</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Leading Collaboration in Online Communities</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Faraj, Samer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kudaravalli, Srinivas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wasko, Molly</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Despite the growing importance of online communities in creating knowledge and facilitating collaboration, there has been limited research examining the role of leaders in such settings. In this paper, we propose a framework that integrates behavioral and structural approaches to explore the antecedents of leadership in online communities focused on knowledge work. Specifically, we propose that sociability and knowledge contribution behaviors as well as structural social capital lead to being identified as a leader by members of the online community. We test this framework using social network, survey, and message-level content analysis data collected from three different online communities focused on technical topics. The results from our zero inflated negative binomial models, with 6,709 messages from 976 individuals, provide strong support for the framework that is developed in this study. Our study contributes to both theory and practice by identifying the behavioral and structural antecedents of leadership in online communities.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3238&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Online leadership</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>leader behaviors</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online communities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>structural social capital</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge collaboration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>network analysis</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3239</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Patterns in Information Systems Portfolio Prioritization:  Evidence from Decision Tree Induction</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Karhade, Prasanna</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shaw, Michael J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Subramanyam, Ramanath</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Questions pertaining to the locus of information systems (IS) governance have been extensively examined in existing research. However, questions pertaining to the decision rationale applied for IS portfolio prioritization (why are certain initiatives approved, and why are certain others rejected), noted to be a critical component of IS governance, need further investigation. We submit that the IS strategy of a firm is likely to explain the decision rationale it applies to IS portfolio prioritization and maintain that it is critical to ensure this decision rationale is in congruence with the firm’s IS strategy. By extending prior theoretical work on IS strategy types, we develop theoretical profiles of the decision rationale applied to IS portfolio prioritization using three attributes: communicability of decision rationale, consistency in applying decision rationale, and risk appropriateness of decision rationale. Since the decision rationale applied for IS portfolio prioritization is often tacit, unknown even to the decision makers themselves, we employ the decision tree induction methodology to discover this tacit decision rationale. We analyze over 150 IS portfolio prioritization decisions on a multimillion dollar IS portfolio of a multibusiness, Fortune 50 firm and our findings, which support our propositions, indicate that firms that adopt different IS strategies rely on systematically different profiles of decision rationale for IS portfolio prioritization. Implications for IS governance practices are developed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3239&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IS strategy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS portfolio prioritization</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT portfolio management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS governance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT governance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>decision making</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>decision tree induction</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3240</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Mobile Application Usability:  Conceptualization and Instrument Development</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hoehle, Hartmut</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Venkatesh, Viswanath</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper presents a mobile application usability conceptualization and survey instrument following the 10-step procedure recommended by MacKenzie et al. (2011). Specifically, we adapted Apple’s user experience guidelines to develop our conceptualization of mobile application usability that we then developed into 19 first-order constructs that formed 6 second-order constructs. To achieve our objective, we collected four datasets: content validity (n = 318), pretest (n = 440), validation (n = 408), and cross-validation (n = 412). The nomological validity of this instrument was established by examining its impact on two outcomes: continued intention to use and mobile application loyalty. We found that the constructs that represented our mobile application usability conceptualization were good predictors of both outcomes and compared favorably to an existing instrument based on Microsoft’s usability guidelines. In addition to being an exemplar of the recent procedure of MacKenzie et al. to validate an instrument, this work provides a rich conceptualization of an instrument for mobile application usability that can serve as a springboard for future work to understand the impacts of mobile application usability and can be used as a guide to design effective mobile applications.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3240&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Usability</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mobile applications</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>survey instrument development</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>continued use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mobile application loyalty</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mobility</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3241</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Support Structures and Their Impacts on Employee Outcomes:  A Longitudinal Field Study of an Enterprise System Implementation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sykes, Tracy Ann</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Despite the impressive progress in understanding the benefits and challenges related to enterprise system (ES) implementations—such as enterprise resource planning (ERP) systems—little is known about how the support structures traditionally used by organizations to help employees cope with a new ES affect employee outcomes related to the system and their jobs. Likewise, little is known about how existing peer advice ties in the business unit influence these outcomes after an ES implementation. Understanding employee outcomes is critical because of their ramifications for long-term ES success. This paper examines the impacts of four traditional support structures (namely, training, online support, help desk support, and change management support), and peer advice ties on four key employee outcomes (namely, system satisfaction, job stress, job satisfaction, and job performance). This paper also seeks to show that it is peer advice ties that best fill the complex informational needs of employees after an ES implementation by providing the right information at the right time and in the right context. The proposed model was tested in a field study conducted in one business unit of a large telecommunications company and gathered data from 120 supplier liaisons over the course of a year. Both traditional support structures and peer advice ties were found to influence the various outcomes, even after controlling for pre-implementation levels of the dependent variables. In all cases, peer advice ties was the strongest predictor, thus underscoring the importance of this critical internal resource.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3241&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Enterprise systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ES implementation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>peer advice ties</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3242</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:13Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>How Information Technology Governance Mechanisms and Strategic Alignment Influence Organizational Performance:  Insights from a Matched Survey of Business and IT Managers</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Wu, Shelly P.J</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Straub, Detmar W.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liang, Ting-Peng</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Previous research has proposed different types for and contingency factors affecting information technology governance. Yet, in spite of this valuable work, it is still unclear through what mechanisms IT governance affects organizational performance. We make a detailed argument for the mediation of strategic alignment in this process. Strategic alignment remains a top priority for business and IT executives, but theory-based empirical research on the relative importance of the factors affecting strategic alignment is still lagging. By consolidating strategic alignment and IT governance models, this research proposes a nomological model showing how organizational value is created through IT governance mechanisms. Our research model draws upon the resource-based view of the firm and provides guidance on how strategic alignment can mediate the effectiveness of IT governance on organizational performance. As such, it contributes to the knowledge bases of both alignment and IT governance literatures. Using dyadic data collected from 131 Taiwanese companies (cross-validated with archival data from 72 firms), we uncover a positive, significant, and impactful linkage between IT governance mechanisms and strategic alignment and, further, between strategic alignment and organizational performance. We also show that the effect of IT governance mechanisms on organizational performance is fully mediated by strategic alignment. Besides making contributions to construct and measure items in this domain, this research contributes to the theory base by integrating and extending the literature on IT governance and strategic alignment, both of which have long been recognized as critical for achieving organizational goals.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3242&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT governance mechanisms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>strategic alignment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>degree-symmetric measures</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3243</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-06-12T15:50:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Errata Note</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss2/13</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3243&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2941</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-07-06T15:19:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Action Design Research</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sein, Maung K</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Henfridsson, Ola</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Purao, Sandeep</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rossi, Matti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lindgren, Rikard</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Design research (DR) positions information technology artifacts at the core of the Information Systems discipline. However, dominant DR thinking takes a technological view of the IT artifact, paying scant attention to its shaping by the organizational context. Consequently, existing DR methods focus on building the artifact and relegate evaluation to a subsequent and separate phase. They value technological rigor at the cost of organizational relevance, and fail to recognize that the artifact emerges from interaction with the organizational context even when its initial design is guided by the researchers’ intent.
We propose action design research (ADR) as a new DR method to address this problem. ADR reflects the premise that IT artifacts are ensembles shaped by the organizational context during development and use. The method conceptualizes the research process as containing the inseparable and inherently interwoven activities of building the IT artifact, intervening in the organization, and evaluating it concurrently. The essay describes the stages of ADR and associated principles that encapsulate its underlying beliefs and values. We illustrate ADR through a case of competence management at Volvo IT.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2011-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol35/iss1/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2941&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Action design research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>action research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>design research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>emergence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ensemble artifact</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational intervention</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>research method</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3256</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Table of Contents, Volume 39, Issue 3</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3256&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3244</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:33Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments:  Inflection Point:  Looking Back or Looking Forward?</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Goes, Paulo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3244&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Editor&#39;s Comments</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3245</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Fairness in the Institutional Valuation of Business Journals</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Templeton, Gary F.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lewis, Bruce R</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The fairness of performance evaluation is a concern for all professions, and the appraisal of research output is of particular interest to business scholars and academic administrators. We describe research assessment as a process of social construction that is heavily influenced by journal valuation in business schools. Using journal quality data from multiple sources, we empirically investigate whether the journals in each of eight business disciplines (Accounting, Economics, Finance, Information Systems, Management, Marketing, Operations Management, and Quantitative Methods) are treated evenly across the board. Specifically, we explore whether each business discipline exhibits recognition fairness (i.e., actual institutional journal evaluations are the same as market expectations) and inclusion fairness (i.e., actual availability of publication space in top journals being the same as market expectations). Our findings indicate that faculty in some disciplines enjoy an advantage, while faculty in other fields are disadvantaged. Consequently, we offer recommendations to ameliorate this inequity.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3245&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Journal valuation fairness</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>institutional and public business journal lists</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>citation metrics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>research evaluation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social constructionism</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3246</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:36Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Genres of Inquiry in Design-Science Research:  Justification and Evaluation of Knowledge Production</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Baskerville, Richard L</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kaul, Mala</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Storey, Veda C.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Recognizing that design is at the core of information systems development has led to a design-science research paradigm where differing kinds of knowledge goals give form to differing kinds of knowledge processes within a single study. This paper analyzes knowledge production in design-science research to explain how an endogenous form of pluralism characterizes such studies, making it problematic to associate any design-science study with a single view of knowledge production. Instead, a design-science research study exhibits up to four different modes of reasoning, called genres of inquiry. These genres are derived from two dualities that contrast differing knowledge goals and differing knowledge scope in the knowledge production process. The first duality arises from the sometimes seemingly contradictory knowledge goals of science versus design. The second duality reflects the contradiction between the scope of the knowledge produced, which may be idiographic or nomothetic. The evolutionary and iterative nature of a design-science study compels different knowledge goals and scope at different moments throughout a project. Because of this momentary nature, a single design-science study can be associated with multiple genres of inquiry. This understanding of the variety in the genres of inquiry advances the discourse on the nature of design-science research and the justification and evaluation of its outcomes. Consequently, a corresponding set of criteria for knowledge justification and evaluation is provided for each genre of inquiry.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3246&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Design science research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>genres of inquiry</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>evaluation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>duality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge scope</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge goal</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge moment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>centrality of knowledge</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>idiographic science</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>nomothetic science</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>endogenous pluralism</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3248</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Jamming with Social Media:  How Cognitive Structuring of Organizing Vision Facets Affects IT Innovation Diffusion</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Miranda, S</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kim, Inchan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Summers, Jama D.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Organizing vision theory is an institutional alternative to the economic-rationality view of IT innovation diffusion. Institutional theorists have called for more attention to cognitive processes and structures in order to understand institutional mechanisms. Our objective was to unpack the cognitive structure of an organizing vision to understand its role in the diffusion of IT innovations. We focus on the know-why component of organizing visions and on social media as an IT innovation. In a two-stage study, Stage I leveraged schema theory, the &#34;orders of worth&#34; framework’s six justificatory principles, and relational class analysis to discover the hierarchical structure of the social media organizing vision. This resulted in a view of the organizing vision as comprised of four schemas, which we conceptualized as visions-in-use, and ten nested business use cases, each comprised of different combinations of the six principles. Based on this understanding, Stage II explored how community appropriations of visions-in-use and business use cases from the repertoire provided by an organizing vision shape four facets of an organizing vision—coherence, continuity, clarity, and diversity—and how these facets influence diffusion of the IT innovation. We found that the two vision facets we surfaced— clarity and diversity—are essential to understanding diffusion and how and why coherence and continuity matter to diffusion. Much as the &#34;vision&#34; of a musical jam session emerges from players’ multivocal performances, an organizing vision emerges from community members’ multivocal discourse about an IT innovation. Just as a jam session depends on a structure of rules and individual player creativity, diffusion of an IT innovation depends on an organizing vision that offers prospective adopters a well-defined repertoire of moves to choose from, yet affords them the freedom to improvise.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3248&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT innovation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizing vision</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social media</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>schema</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>relational class analysis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>quantitative grounded theory</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3249</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:40Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Information Technology Use as a Learning Mechanism:  The Impact of IT Use on Knowledge Transfer Effectiveness, Absorptive Capacity, and Franchisee Performance</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Iyengar, Kishen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sweeney, Jeffrey R.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Montealegre, Ramiro</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This study aims to contribute to the literature through the theoretical development and empirical investigation of the role of information technology use in organizational learning. We develop a theoretical framework that unpacks organizational learning into mechanisms and outcomes. The outcomes of organizational learning are distinguished at two levels: first-order and second-order. Based on the framework, we propose a research model set in the franchising context. We conceptualize franchisee use of IT provided by the franchisor as an important learning mechanism that impacts knowledge transfer effectiveness (first-order outcome) and absorptive capacity (second-order outcome). Further, the influence of IT use on financial performance is mediated through absorptive capacity. The model was tested on a sample of 783 independently owned real-estate franchisees using a comprehensive dataset comprised of primary and secondary data. The results indicate that IT use is an important learning mechanism for franchisees by impacting knowledge transfer effectiveness and absorptive capacity. In turn, absorptive capacity mediates the relationship between IT use and financial performance. The empirical support for the research model serves to affirm the underlying learning mechanisms–outcomes framework. The results are stable across the choice of statistical method and the operationalization of financial performance. Theoretical contributions, implications for practice, and limitations of the study are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3249&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational learning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge transfer effectiveness</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>absorptive capacity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT value</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>franchising</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3250</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Organizational Path Constitution in Technological Innovation:  Evidence from Rural Telehealth</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Singh, Rajendra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mathiassen, Lars</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mishra, Abhay Nath</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Path constitution theory has emerged as a promising combination of two contrasting perspectives on technological innovation: path dependence, which focuses on historically embedded, contingent processes that are more or less beyond the control of actors, and path creation, which emphasizes mindful contributions from powerful actors. However, the current path constitution literature focuses on macro- and multi-level inquiry without addressing the specific processes, opportunities, and challenges related to organizational (micro-level) technological innovation. Against this backdrop, we draw on the innovation and path literature as well as a case study of telehealth innovation in a public health organization to theorize how technological innovation paths constitute in organizational contexts. The proposed theory distinguishes between innovation path status and innovation path trajectory to help researchers understand and explain how organizations transform and reinforce path constitution patterns, how innovation paths may merge with or separate from other paths, and how organizations may arrive at a lock-in that challenges them to break out from dominant and seemingly irreversible action patterns.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3250&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Technological innovation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>innovation path constitution</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>path creation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>path dependence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>rural telehealth</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social construction of technology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>public health</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3251</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:42Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Comparing Potential and Actual Innovators:  An Empirical Study of Mobile Data Services Innovation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kankanhalli, Atreyi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hua Ye, Jonathan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Teo, Hock Hai</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Firms are increasingly opening up their innovation efforts to allow users to tap into the benefits they can offer, such as mobile data service (MDS) innovation on iOS and Google Android platforms. For this purpose, platforms typically provide toolkits to facilitate user participation, aiming to create an ecosystem for sustainable innovation. However, with the barriers to user innovation and attrition of existing innovators, it could be challenging for firms to attract and sustain users’ MDS innovation. With the possible benefits from user innovation, and considering the challenges faced, firms need to understand how to influence potential user innovators to take part and to encourage extant user innovators to innovate again. However, there is a lack of comprehensive research and understanding of what drives users’ intentions to innovate services and the differences in the antecedents of such intention between potential and actual user innovators. Further, although prior studies have suggested that toolkits can support user innovation, little research has theorized and empirically tested their influence. Motivated thus, this study proposes a model based on (1)　user innovation theory to explain the antecedents (including toolkit support) of user MDS innovation intention and (2)　construal level theory to explain the differential effects of the antecedents for actual and potential user innovators. We tested the model through survey data from potential and actual MDS user innovators on Google Android and iOS platforms. We find that trend leadership and anticipated extrinsic reward influence both potential and actual user innovators’ intentions to innovate. However, anticipated recognition and toolkit support affect only actual user innovators, while anticipated enjoyment affects only potential user innovators. Interestingly, toolkit support strengthens the influence of anticipated enjoyment for actual user innovators but weakens its influence for potential user innovators. Further, potential user innovators value anticipated extrinsic rewards less than actual innovators do. The implications for research and practice are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3251&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>User service innovation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mobile data services</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>user innovation theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>construal level theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>potential and actual user innovators</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3252</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:43Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Competing for Attention:  An Empirical Study of Online Reviewers&#39; Strategic Behavior</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Shen, Wenqi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hu, Yu Jeffrey</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rees Ulmer, Jackie</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Top online reviewers who reliably gain consumers’ attention stand to make significant financial gains and monetize the amount of attention and reputation they have earned. This study explores how online reviewers strategically choose the right product to review and the right rating to post so that they can gain attention and enhance reputation. Using book reviews from Amazon and Barnes &#38; Noble (BN), we find that reviewers on Amazon, where a reviewer ranking system quantifies reviewers’ online reputations, are sensitive to the competition among existing reviews and thus tend to avoid crowded review segments. However, on BN, which does not include such a ranking mechanism, reviewers do not respond to the competition effect. In addition, reviewers on Amazon post more differentiated ratings compared with reviewers on BN since the competition for attention on Amazon is more intense than on BN. Overall, reviewers on Amazon behave more strategically than reviewers on BN. This study yields important managerial implications for companies to improve their design of online review systems and enhance their understanding of reviewers’ strategic behaviors.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3252&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Online attention</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>scarcity of attention</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>competing for attention</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online product reviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>user-generated content</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3253</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:45Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Extending ICT4D Studies:  The Value of Critical Research</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Lin, Cecilia I. C.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kuo, Feng-Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Myers, Michael D.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The purpose of this paper is to demonstrate the value of critical research for information and communications technology for development (ICT4D) studies. Most previous IS research on ICT4D projects is interpretive and has focused on the immediate organizational context, but there are very few critical studies that have engaged in macro sociopolitical analyses regarding institutional change. Hence we extend previous IS research on ICT4D by adopting a critical research perspective on the macro sociopolitical context within which most ICT4D projects take place. We illustrate this with an ethnographic study of a project that was intended to improve the education and social welfare of the aboriginal people in Taiwan. On the surface the project was tremendously successful; it became a showcase on national radio and TV showing how ICT could be used to support underprivileged children. However, our research uncovered a different story altogether—a story of the aboriginal people themselves feeling marginalized and without much of a voice. We use concepts from postcolonial theory to make sense of these two contradictory stories. We found that the interrelationship between the macro sociopolitical context and the local organizational context of the ICT4D project is the key to understanding what went wrong, something which we would not have discovered if we had taken the traditional approach. The postcolonial context is powerful and pervasive, hampering any real progress.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3253&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>ICT4D</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>development</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>critical research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>postcolonial theory</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3254</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:46Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Exhaustion from Information System Career Experience:  Implications for Turn-Away Intention</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Armstrong, Deborah J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brooks, Nita G.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Riemenschneider, Cynthia K.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>While the U.S. economy is recovering slowly, reports tell us that the supply of information systems (IS) professionals is declining and demand is once again on the rise. With organizations challenged in their efforts to hire additional staff, IS professionals are being asked to do even more, often leading to burnout, turnover, and turn-away intentions. Building on Ahuja et al.’s (2007) work on turnover intentions and using the job demands– resources model of burnout as an organizing framework for the antecedents to exhaustion from IS career experience (EISCE), this illustrative research note draws attention to exhaustion in IS professionals that spans an individual’s professional career. Findings indicate that IS professionals’ perceived workload (demand) was associated with higher levels of EISCE, whereas fairness and perceived control of career (resources) were associated with lower levels of EISCE. The influence of EISCE on affective commitment to the IS profession (ACISP) was found to be negative and, ultimately, ACISP fully mediated the effect of EISCE on the intention to turn away from an IS career. The results suggest the importance of studying IS professionals’ perceptions regarding the demands and resources associated with working in the IS field when testing exhaustion across IS career experience.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3254&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IS personnel</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>workforce</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>burnout</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>exhaustion</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>affective commitment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>turn-away intention</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>occupational turnover</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3255</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-08-27T16:44:47Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Friendships in Online Peer-to-Peer Lending:  Pipes, Prisms, and Relational Herding</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Liu, De</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brass, Daniel J.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lu, Yong (Eric)</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chen, Dongyu</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper investigates how friendship relationships act as pipes, prisms, and herding signals in a large online, peer-to-peer (P2P) lending site. By analyzing decisions of lenders, we find that friends of the borrower, especially close offline friends, act as financial pipes by lending money to the borrower. On the other hand, the prism effect of friends’ endorsements via bidding on a loan negatively affects subsequent bids by third parties. However, when offline friends of a potential lender, especially close friends, place a bid, a relational herding effect occurs as potential lenders are likely to follow their offline friends with a bid.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/13</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3255&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Peer-to-peer lending</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>friendship relationships</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social networks</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>prism effect</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>herding</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2372</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-10-21T16:52:57Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>A Cross-Cultural Study on Escalation of Commitment Behavior in Software Projects</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Keil, Mark</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tan, Bernard C. Y.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei, Kwok-Kee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Saarinen, Timo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tuunainen, Virpi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wassenaar, Arjen</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2000-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol24/iss2/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2372&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Software project management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>escalation of commitment behavior</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>sunk cost</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>risk propensity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>uncertainty avoidance</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2721</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-06T17:13:34Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Contributing Knowledge to Electronic Repositories:  An Empirical Investigation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kankanhalli, Atreyi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tan, Bernard C. Y.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei, Kwok-Kee</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Organizations are attempting to leverage their knowledge resources by employing knowledge management (KM) systems, a key form of which are electronic knowledge repositories (EKRs). A large number of KM initiatives fail due to reluctance of employees to share knowledge through these systems. Motivated by such concerns, this study formulates and tests a theoretical model to explain EKR usage by knowledge contributors. The model employs social exchange theory to identify cost and benefit factors affecting EKR usage, and social capital theory to account for the moderating influence of contextual factors. The model is validated through a large-scale survey of public sector organizations. The results reveal that knowledge self-efficacy and enjoyment in helping others significantly impact EKR usage by knowledge contributors. Contextual factors (generalized trust, pro-sharing norms, and identification) moderate the impact of codification effort, reciprocity, and organizational reward on EKR usage, respectively. It can be seen that extrinsic benefits (reciprocity and organizational reward) impact EKR usage contingent on particular contextual factors whereas the effects of intrinsic benefits (knowledge self-efficacy and enjoyment in helping others) on EKR usage are not moderated by contextual factors. The loss of knowledge power and image do not appear to impact EKR usage by knowledge contributors. Besides contributing to theory building in KM, the results of this study inform KM practice.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol29/iss1/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2721&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>electronic knowledge repositories</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge contribution</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social exchange</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social capital</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3257</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:10Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Table of Contents, Volume 39, Issue 4</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3257&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3258</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:11Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments:  The Business of Business Data Science in IS Journals</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saar-Tsechansky, Maytal</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3258&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3259</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Ambient Awareness and Knowledge Acquisition:  Using Social Media to Learn &#34;Who Knows What&#34; and &#34;Who Knows Whom&#34;</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Leonardi, Paul M.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The argument proffered in this paper is that use of enterprise social networking technologies can increase the accuracy of people’s metaknowledge (knowledge of &#34;who knows what&#34; and &#34;who knows whom&#34;) at work. The results of a quasi-natural field experiment in which only one of two matched-sample groups within a large financial services firm was given access to the enterprise social networking technology for six months revealed that by making people’s communications with specific partners visible to others in the organization, the technology enabled observers to become aware of the communications occurring amongst their coworkers and to make inferences about what and whom those coworkers knew based on the contents of the messages they sent and to whom they were sent. Consequently only individuals in the group that used the social networking technology for six months improved the accuracy of their metaknowledge (a 31% improvement in knowledge of who knows what and an 88% improvement in knowledge of who knows whom). There were no improvements in the other group over the same time period. Based on these findings, how technologically enabled &#34;ambient awareness&#34;—awareness of ambient communications occurring amongst others in the organization—can be an important antecedent for knowledge acquisition is discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3259&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Social networking sites</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge sharing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational learning</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>accuracy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>communication</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>collaboration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>transparency</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3260</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:14Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Work Harder or Work Smarter?  Information Technology and Resource Allocation in Healthcare Processes</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Yeow, Adrian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Goh, Kim Huat</dc:creator>
<dc:description>While the impacts of health information technology (HIT) are widely studied, prior research presents mixed findings. In this study, a granular examination of the impact of HIT systems on how resources are allocated to healthcare tasks and processes was undertaken. A longitudinal field study that combined interview, archival, observation, and survey data was conducted. The effects of telemedicine on the input allocative efficiency of the healthcare process through the reallocation of organizational resources was evaluated and an assessment of whether gains in allocative efficiency resulted in improvements in organizational outcomes, such as lower hospitalization rates and lower uncertainty in patient wait time, was conducted. Applying the theory of swift and even flow, our findings suggest that the gains in allocative efficiency for some processes are associated with improved organizational outcomes.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3260&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Healthcare</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>telemedicine</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>stochastic frontier analysis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>resource allocations</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3261</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:15Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Software Process Diversity:  Conceptualization, Measurement, and Analysis of Impact on Project Performance</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ramasubbu, Narayan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bharadwaj, Anandhi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tayi, Giri Kumar</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This article investigates software process diversity, defined as the project condition arising out of the simultaneous use of multiple software development process frameworks within a single project. Software process diversity is conceptualized as the response of a project team to such contingencies as requirements volatility, design and technological novelty, customer involvement, and the level of organizational process compliance enforced on the project. Moreover, we conceptualize that the degree of fit (or match) between a project’s software process diversity and the level of process compliance enforced on the project impacts overall project performance. This conceptualization was empirically tested by utilizing data collected from 410 large commercial software projects of a multinational firm. The results show that higher levels of requirements volatility, design and technological novelty, and customer involvement increased software process diversity within a project. However, software process diversity decreased relative to increases in the level of process compliance enforced on the project. A higher degree of fit between the process diversity and process compliance of a project, rather than the effects of those variables independently, was found to be significantly associated with a higher level of project performance, as measured in terms of project productivity and software quality. These results indicate that increasing software process diversity in response to project-level contingencies improves project performance only when there is a concomitant increase in organizational process compliance efforts. The implications of these results for research are discussed and prescriptive guidelines derived to manage the fit between process diversity and process compliance for improving software project performance.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3261&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Software process diversity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>process compliance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>plan-based processes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>agile processes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>software engineering</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>productivity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>quality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>fit as matching</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3262</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:16Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Information Technology Impacts on Firm Performance:  An Extension of Kohli and Devaraj (2003)</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sabherwal, Rajiv</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeyaraj, Anand</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Despite the importance of investing in information technology, research on business value of information technology (BVIT) shows contradictory results, raising questions about the reasons for divergence. Kohli and Devaraj (2003) provided valuable insights into this issue based on a meta-analysis of 66 BVIT studies. This paper extends Kohli and Devaraj by examining the influences on BVIT through a meta-analysis of 303 studies published between 1990 and 2013. We found that BVIT increases when the study does not consider IT investment, does not use profitability measure of value, and employs primary data sources, fewer IT-related antecedents, and larger sample size. Considerations of IT alignment, IT adoption and use, and interorganizational IT strengthen the relationship between IT investment on BVIT, whereas the focus on environmental theories dampens the same relationship. However, the use of productivity measures of value, the number of dependent variables, the economic region, the consideration of IT assets and IT infrastructure or capability, and the consideration of IT sophistication do not affect BVIT. Finally, BVIT increases over time with IT progress. Implications for future research and practice are discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3262&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information technology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>business value of information technology</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>firm performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>meta-analysis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>investment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>payoff</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3263</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:17Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>What Do Systems Users Have to Fear?  Using Fear Appeals to Engender Threats and Fear that Motivate Protective Security Behaviors</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Boss, Scott R.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Galletta, Dennis F</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lowry, Paul Benjamin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Moody, Gregory</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Polak, Peter</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Because violations of information security (ISec) and privacy have become ubiquitous in both personal and work environments, academic attention to ISec and privacy has taken on paramount importance. Consequently, a key focus of ISec research has been discovering ways to motivate individuals to engage in more secure behaviors. Over time, the protection motivation theory (PMT) has become a leading theoretical foundation used in ISec research to help motivate individuals to change their security-related behaviors to protect themselves and their organizations. Our careful review of the foundation for PMT identified four opportunities for improving ISec PMT research. First, extant ISec studies do not use the full nomology of PMT constructs. Second, only one study uses fear-appeal manipulations, even though these are a core element of PMT. Third, virtually no ISec study models or measures fear. Fourth, whereas these studies have made excellent progress in predicting security intentions, none of them have addressed actual security behaviors.
This article describes the theoretical foundation of these four opportunities for improvement. We tested the nomology of PMT, including manipulated fear appeals, in two different ISec contexts that model the modern theoretical treatment of PMT more closely than do extant ISec studies. The first data collection was a longitudinal study in the context of data backups. The second study was a short-term cross-sectional study in the context of anti-malware software. Our new model demonstrated better results and stronger fit than the existing models and confirms the efficacy of the four potential improvements we identified.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3263&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information security</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>protection motivation theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>system backups</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>model comparison</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>fear appeals</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>threat</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>coping</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>intentions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3264</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:19Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Fit and Misfit of Plural Sourcing Strategies and IT-Enabled Process Integration Capabilities:  Consequences of Firm Performance in the U.S. Electric Utility Industry</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Rai, Arun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Arikan, Ilgaz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pye, Jessica</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tiwana, Amrit</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Recent work has shown that a firm’s plural sourcing strategy, which determines how much it chooses to make versus how much it chooses to buy, requires consideration of the complementarities and constraints that affect the differential advantages of making and buying. Elaborating on this perspective, we theorize how (mis)fit between a firm’s plural sourcing strategy of simultaneously making and buying and its development of information technology (IT) enabled interfirm and intrafirm process integration capabilities influences firm performance in deregulated markets. We position our theory development and empirical tests in the context of the power-generation segment of the U.S. electric utility industry (EUI), an asset-intensive industry that has been deregulated to promote the separation of key value chain activities (i.e., generation, transmission, and distribution) and the development of wholesale energy markets. We draw on the transaction cost economics, coordination costs, and IT capabilities perspectives to theorize that a firm achieves fit (realizing performance benefits) by increasing market sourcing intensity (MSI)—or, how much it buys relative to how much it makes— and developing IT-enabled interfirm process integration capability for external coordination with the market, or misfit (realizing performance penalties) by increasing MSI and developing IT-enabled intrafirm process integration capability for coordinating internal production. We collated data from archival sources for 342 utility firms in the power-generation segment to construct a panel dataset for the period 1994–2004 on (1)　firms’ MSI from wholesale electricity markets, (2)　firms’ IT investment decisions to develop interfirm and intrafirm process integration capabilities, (3)　measures of firm performance, and (4)　several control variables related to exogenous shocks (i.e., regulatory change, oil crisis), region of operation, and firm-level factors. Our results suggest that fit between MSI and the development of IT-enabled interfirm process integration capability improves firm profitability, assessed by return on assets, and misfit between MSI and the development of IT-enabled intrafirm process integration capability extracts penalties in firm profitability. We also find evidence that fit between MSI and the development of IT-enabled interfirm process integration capability improves market valuation, assessed by Tobin’s Q, and asset turnover, assessed by operating revenue/total assets. We discuss the implications of our findings for the development of IT capabilities to accompany a firm’s plural sourcing strategy and the literature on IT business value.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3264&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Plural sourcing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>market sourcing intensity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT-enabled process integration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT capabilities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>firm performance</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT business value</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3266</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:21Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Me. My Self, and I(T):  Conceptualizating Information Technology Identity and its Implications</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Carter, Michelle</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Grover, Varun</dc:creator>
<dc:description>As social roles and relationships become increasingly inseparable from people’s interactions with information technologies (ITs), new constructs representing this intertwinement are needed to expand understandings of human behavior. As part of that endeavor, this paper draws on structural symbolic interactionist identity theories to systematically develop a conceptual definition of one such construct, IT identity—defined as the extent to which an individual views use of an IT as integral to his or her sense of self—as a new form of identity. The construct is framed within a theoretical model. Our goal is to facilitate the establishment of IT identity as an important and relevant construct that can improve our understanding of a variety of phenomena. In doing so, this paper makes three contributions to the information systems (IS) literature. First, it delineates current understanding of IT as a medium, determinant, or consequent of identity. Second, it defines the conceptual domain and theme of IT identity, which is necessary for investigating the construct’s theoretical influence. Third, it demonstrates the utility of IT identity to a wide range of IS topics relating to how people express, maintain, and expand their self-concepts. In doing so, it offers potential directions and opportunities for IS researchers to incorporate this novel concept into IS research.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3266&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>human behavior</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>individual IT use</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT embeddedness</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>theory development</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3267</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:22Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Cultural Sensemaking in Offshore Information Technology Service Suppliers:   A Cultural Frame Perspective</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Su, Ning</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In today’s global IT outsourcing relationships, individual employees need to operate effectively in culturally diverse environments. Such intercultural interactions can be especially challenging for members of IT service suppliers based in offshore locations. Through an in-depth qualitative case study of one of the largest China-based IT service firms with diverse clients from Japan, the United States, and China, this research elaborates the cultural sensemaking activities of the supplier’s individual employees. Specifically, drawing on the dynamic constructivist view of culture, this study develops the construct of &#34;cultural frames&#34; in the context of global IT outsourcing to characterize the knowledge structures guiding an individual’s collaboration with diverse clients. A portfolio of cultural frames emerges and evolves through the individual’s cultural sensemaking activities, which consist of the iterative enactment, alignment, and retention of cultural frames. In the cultural sensemaking process, the activity of frame bridging, in particular, creates significant value for the outsourcing relationship, and is especially salient among bicultural employees.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3267&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT outsourcing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT supplier</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cultural sensemaking</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cultural frame</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>China</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3268</identifier>
		<datestamp>2015-11-19T17:41:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Subject/Author Index for Volume 39</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015-12-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss4/12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3268&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3247</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-01-04T19:32:05Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Vocal Minority and Silent Majority:  How Do Online Ratings Reflect Population Perceptions of Quality?</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gao, Guodong (Gordon)</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Greenwood, Brad N.</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Agarwal, Ritu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>McCullough, Jeffrey S.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Consumer-generated ratings typically share an objective of illuminating the quality of a product or service for other buyers. While ratings have become ubiquitous and influential on the Internet, surprisingly little empirical research has investigated how these online assessments reflect the opinion of the population at large, especially in the domain of professional services where quality is often opaque to consumers. Building on the word-of-mouth literature, we examine the relationship between online ratings and population perceptions of physician quality. We leverage a unique dataset which includes direct measures of both the offline population’s perception of physician quality and consumer-generated online reviews. As a result, we are able to examine how online ratings reflect patients’ opinions about physician quality. In sharp contrast to the widely voiced concerns by medical practitioners, we find that physicians who are rated lower in quality by the patient population are less likely to be rated online. Although ratings provided online are positively correlated with patient population opinions, the online ratings tend to be exaggerated at the upper end of the quality spectrum. This study is the first to provide empirical evidence of the relationship between online ratings and the underlying consumer-perceived quality, and extends prior research on online word-of-mouth to the domain of professional services.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-09-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol39/iss3/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3247&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Online ratings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>physician quality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>online word-of-mouth</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>professional services</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>informativeness</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-2370</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-01-05T16:30:37Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Information Technology Development Creativity:  A Case Study of Attempted Radical Change</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Cooper, Randolph</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2000-06-01T07:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol24/iss2/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=2370&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Creativity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>innovation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>diffusion</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information system development</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information technology requirements</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>reengineering</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>radical change</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>organizational change</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3269</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:00:55Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Table of Contents</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Quarterly, MIS</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3269&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Contents</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3270</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:01:02Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Editor&#39;s Comments:  The MIS Quarterly Trifecta:  Impact, Range, Speed</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Rai, Arun</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3270&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>


		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3271</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:01:12Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>An Exploratory Study of the Formation and Impact of Electronic Service Failures</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Tan, Chee-Wee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benbasat, Izak</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cenfetelli, Ronald T.</dc:creator>
<dc:description>E-commerce service failures have been the bane of e-commerce, compelling customers to either abandon transactions entirely or switch to traditional brick-and-mortar establishments. Yet, there is a paucity of studies that investigates how such failures manifest on e-commerce websites and their impact on consumers. This paper, therefore, synthesizes extant literature on e-service and system success to arrive at a novel classification system that delineates e-commerce service failures into information, functional, and system categories, each with its own set of constituent dimensions. Extending expectation disconfirmation theory (EDT), we further distinguish among disconfirmed outcome, process, and cost expectancies as major consequences of e-commerce service failures. A theoretical model of e-commerce service failure classifications and their consequences was constructed together with testable propositions that relate the three failure categories to consumers’ disconfirmed expectancies. Finally, we explore the validity of our theoretical model based on descriptive accounts of actual occurrences of e-commerce service failures and their corresponding consequences. Consistent with our theoretical model, information and functional failures were found to be associated with disconfirmed outcome and process expectancies respectively. System failures, on the other hand, do not affect consumers’ disconfirmed expectancies, thereby contradicting our predictions. Post hoc analysis on constituent dimensions of information, functional, and system failures yielded additional insights on the preceding observations.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/3</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3271&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>E-commerce service failure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>expectation disconfirmation theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information failure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>functional failure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>system failure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>disconfirmed outcome expectancy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>disconfirmed process expectancy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>disconfirmed cost expectancy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>critical incident technique (CIT)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>qualitative comparative analysis (QCA)</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3272</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:01:23Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Free Versys For-a-Fee:  The Impact of a Paywall on the Pattern and Effectiveness of Word-of-Mouth via Social Media</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Oh, Hyelim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Animesh, Animesh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pinsonneault, Alain</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Information goods providers such as print newspapers are experimenting with different pricing models for their online content. Despite research on the topic, it is still not clear how information pricing strategy influences word-of-mouth (WOM) via social media, which has become a dominant channel for raising awareness about a newspaper’s articles and attracting new visitors to its website. Using The New York Times’ paywall rollout as a natural experiment, our study examines how the implementation of paywall by a firm (i.e., a shift from &#34;free&#34; to &#34;for-a-fee&#34;) influences the pattern and effectiveness of online WOM in social media. Our results indicate that implementing a paywall (i.e., charging for content that was earlier available for free) has a disproportionate impact on WOM for popular and niche articles, creating a longer tail in the WOM (i.e., content sharing) distribution. Further, we find that the impact of WOM on the NYT’s website traffic weakens significantly after the introduction of a paywall. These results show that a paywall has implications for product and promotion strategies. The study offers novel and important implications for the theory and practice of strategic use of social media and paywall.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/4</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3272&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Information goods</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information pricing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>paywall</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>social media</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>long tail</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>word-of-mouth</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>website traffic</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3273</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:01:38Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Contract Design Choises and the Balance of Ex Ante and Ex Post Transaction Costs in Software Development Outsourcing</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Benaroch, Michel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lichtenstein, Yossi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fink, Lior</dc:creator>
<dc:description>This paper examines multiple contract design choices in the context of transaction and relational attributes and consequent ex ante and ex post transaction costs. It focuses on two understudied themes in the IT outsourcing literature. First, while the literature is predominantly concerned with opportunism and consequent ex post hazard costs that contracts can safeguard against, parties to a contract also economize on ex ante transaction costs by their choice of contract type and contract extensiveness. Second, the literature studies the aggregate extensiveness of contracts rather than of distinct contract functions: safeguarding, coordination, and adaptability. Against this backdrop, our research model portrays a nuanced picture that is anchored in the following theoretical interpretation: transaction and relational attributes have implications on specific ex ante and ex post transaction costs, and these implications can be balanced by respective choices in both contract type and the extensiveness of specific contract functions. These two contract design choices complement and substitute for each other in their ability to economize on specific transaction costs. Our analysis of 210 software development outsourcing contracts finds that explanatory power increases when analyzing the extensiveness of individual contract functions rather than the aggregate contract extensiveness, highlighting subtle competing influences that are otherwise masked by an aggregate measure. Our analysis also shows that a preference for time-and-material contracts counteracts the effect of certain transaction attributes on contract extensiveness, and even cancels it out in the case of transaction uncertainty.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/5</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3273&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Contract functions (safeguarding</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>coordination</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>adaptability)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>contract extensiveness</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>contract type</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>ex ante and ex post transaction costs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>transaction cost economics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>software development outsourcing</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3274</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:01:49Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Valuing Information Technology Related Intangible Assets</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Saunders, Adam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brynjolfsson, Erik</dc:creator>
<dc:description>In this article, we assess the value of information technology related intangible assets and then use data on business practices and management capabilities to understand how this value is distributed across firms. Using a panel of 127 firms over the period 2003–2006, we replicate and extend the finding from Brynjolfsson, Hitt, and Yang (2002) that $1 of computer hardware is correlated with more than $10 of market value. We account for the &#34;missing $9&#34; by broadening the definition of IT to include capitalized software, and then include all purchased and internally developed software, other internal IT services, IT consulting, and IT-related training (whether or not it is capitalized by the firm). In addition, we use data on IT-related business practices in order to analyze the distribution of IT-related intangibles within the sample. Our results suggest that the &#34;invisible&#34; IT not accounted for on balance sheets is being priced into the market value of firms. We also estimate that there is a 45% to 76% premium in market value for the firms with the highest organizational IT capabilities (based on separate measures of human resource practices, management practices, internal IT use, external IT use, and Internet capabilities), as compared to those with the lowest organizational IT capabilities. Our results thus suggest that contributions of IT to value depend heavily on other factors, and are not a rising tide that lifts all boats.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/6</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3274&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT value</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>market value</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT-related intangibles</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT capabilities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>intangible assets</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>R&#38;D value</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>brand value</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3275</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:02:00Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Competitive Bundling in Information Markets:  A Seller-Side Analysis</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Raghunathan, Srinivasan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarkar, Sumit</dc:creator>
<dc:description>The emerging field of data analytics and the increasing importance of data and information in decision making has created a large market for buying and selling information and information-related services. In this market, for some types of information products, it is common for a consumer to purchase the same type of information product from multiple sources. In other situations, a consumer may buy different types of information products from different sources and synthesize the information. On the seller side, bundling of different types of information products appears to have emerged as a key design strategy to improve profitability. This paper examines bundling decisions of a duopoly in the information market in which each seller offers two (or more) types of information products. A pair of competing information products from the two sellers can be substitutes or complements and consumers may find it profitable to purchase the same type of information from both sellers. We show that bundling by both sellers emerges as the equilibrium outcome when (at least) one competing pair consists of substitutes and (at least) one pair consists of complements. In this case, bundling by both sellers benefits them both by softening the price competition between their offerings. Softening of competition does not occur when all competing pairs in the bundles have only substitutes (complements) even if the degree of substitutability (complementarity) between products within a pair varies across pairs, resulting in an equilibrium in which each information type is sold separately by both sellers.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/7</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3275&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Bundling</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>pricing</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>competition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>analytical models</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>information markets</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3276</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:02:09Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>When Does Repository KMS Use Lift Performance?  The Role of Alternative Knowledge Sources and Task Environments</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kim, Seung Hyun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mukhopadhyay, Tridas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kraut, Robert E</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Despite a general consensus that use of information technology (IT) is an important link between IT investments and performance, the extant literature provides only a limited explanation as to when the use of IT lifts performance. We posit that the impact of knowledge management systems (KMS) usage is contingent on users’ alternative sources of knowledge as well as their specific task environments. We investigate under what conditions repository KMS use leads to higher performance outcomes in a retail grocery context. We use a unique longitudinal dataset composed of objective measures of KMS use and sales performance of 273 managers over 146 weeks collected from a retail grocery chain. We obtain two main results. First, we find a diminishing impact of KMS use for managers who also use other sources of codified knowledge, namely physical or computerized alternative knowledge sources, whereas a complementary relationship seems to exist between KMS use and social sources of knowledge. Second, KMS use produces higher benefits for managers whose task environments require a greater volume of information and knowledge, but smaller benefits for those managers whose task environments demand rapidly changing information and knowledge. Our work contributes to both the IT business value and the KM literature by studying the contingent impact of IT usage while broadening the theoretical scope of the situated knowledge performance framework with a critical empirical test based on fine-grained objective and longitudinal data.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/8</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3276&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Business value of IT</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge management systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>IT usage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge channels</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>contingent impact</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>retail grocery</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>complementarity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>situated knowledge performance framework</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>knowledge management</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3277</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:02:20Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>A Temporally Situated Self-Agency Theory of Information Technology Reinvention</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Nevo, Saggi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nevo, Dorit</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pinsonneault, Alain</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Our knowledge of how users reinvent information technologies (IT) in ways that depart from their intended purposes to achieve new goals is relatively limited. Drawing on a human agency theory that situates actors in the flow of time, this paper develops a theory of IT reinvention. It identifies the key subprocesses of IT reinvention, describes two patterns of reinvention (performance-oriented and mastery-oriented), and explains how the present and the past influence the ambiguities, demands, and dilemmas inherent to each pattern. The outcomes associated with each pattern of IT reinvention are also discussed. The paper provides the theoretical foundations to understand how users reinvent IT as well as new insights into a broader range of post-adoption behaviors.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/9</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3277&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>IT reinvention</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>human agency</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>temporal orientation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>prospective technological capabilities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mastery goals</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>performance goals</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>post-adoption</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>technology adaptation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>process theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>innovation diffusion</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3278</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:02:32Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Deal-Seeking Versus Brand-Seeking:  Search Behaviors and Purchase Propensities in Sponsored Search Platforms</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Im, Il</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jun, Jongkun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Oh, Wonseok</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>JEONG, SEOK-OH</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Using a database of 11,001 unique sponsored search keywords, we investigate the relationship between the characteristics of keywords oriented around deal-seeking and brand-seeking and consumer search behaviors and buying propensities. On the basis of the search depth versus search breadth framework, we hypothesize that deal-seeking keywords elicit a search of greater breadth, whereas brand-seeking keywords induce a search of greater depth. We also explore the moderating effect of product type (search or experience goods) on the relationship between keyword characteristics and consumer search behaviors and how high-demand seasons (e.g., scheduled sales) influence consumers’ search and purchase behaviors. In addition, we estimate the effectiveness of keywords on the basis of their sales-per-cost performance. The findings indicate that search queries containing deal-seeking keywords are associated with higher click-through rates and conversion rates than are search queries without such keywords. We also find that the positive effect of deal-seeking keywords on click-through rates is more pronounced for experience goods than for search goods. However, we identify a negative interaction between experience goods and brand-seeking keywords. A comparison of deal-seeking and brand-seeking keywords in terms of cost effectiveness reveals that deal-seeking keywords generate approximately three times the sales of those produced by brand-seeking keywords.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3278&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Sponsored search</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>deal-seeking</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>brand-seeking</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>experience goods</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>click-through rate</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>conversion rate</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hierarchical generalized linear model</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>propensity score weighting</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

			
<record>
	<header>
		<identifier>oai:aisel.aisnet.org:misq-3279</identifier>
		<datestamp>2016-04-06T18:02:41Z</datestamp>
				<setSpec>publication:journals</setSpec>
				<setSpec>publication:misq</setSpec>
			</header>
	<metadata>
		<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
			<dc:title>Individual&#39;s Internet Security Perceptions and Behaviors:  Polycontextual Contrasts Between the United States and China</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Chen, Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zahedi, Fatemeh &#34;Miriam&#34;</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Little is known about the context sensitivity of users’ online security perceptions and behaviors to national and individual attributes, and there is inadequate research about the spectrum of users’ behaviors in dealing with online security threats. In addressing this gap, this paper draws on two complementary theoretical bases: (1)　the contextualization of the protection motivation theory (PMT) to online security behavior and (2)　a polycontextual lens for the cross-national comparison of users’ security behaviors in the United States and China. The conceptualized model is tested based on 718 survey observations collected from the United States and China. The results support our model and show the divergence between the United States, an exemplar of modern Western society, and China, an exemplar of traditional Eastern society, in forming threat perceptions and in seeking help and avoidance as coping behaviors. Our results also uncovered the significant moderating impacts of espoused culture on the way perceptions of security threats and coping appraisals influence security behaviors. Our findings underline the importance of context-sensitive theory building in security research and provide insights into the motivators and moderators of individuals’ online security behaviors in the two nations.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-01T08:00:00Z</dc:date>
<dc:type>text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:identifier >http://aisel.aisnet.org/misq/vol40/iss1/11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://aisel.aisnet.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=3279&#38;amp;context=misq</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Management Information Systems Quarterly</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>AIS Electronic Library (AISeL)</dc:publisher>

<dc:subject>Individual users</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>protection motivation theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>coping theory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>security behaviors</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>seeking help</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>security self-efficacy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>security response efficacy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>cross-national research</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>espoused national culture</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>polycontextual lens</dc:subject>

		</oai_dc:dc>
	</metadata>
</record>

				
			<resumptionToken completeListSize="1372" cursor="1200">509567/oai_dc/1300//</resumptionToken>
		
		</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>